http://dailysubs.net 500萬的字幕
Credits to explosiveskull for the Sub
www.addic7ed.com.
學分explosiveskull為子
www.addic7ed.com。
Credits to explosiveskull for the Sub
www.addic7ed.com.
固定和同步處理由bozxphd.Enjoy輕彈
Fixed & Synced by bozxphd.Enjoy The Flick
有了這樣的電影 2001 你
突出我們進入了21世紀。
And with that movie 2001, you're
projecting us into the 21st century.
- 我帶了我的兒子喬納森
- 你好。
- I brought along my son Jonathan...
- Hi.
誰在2001年會
相同的年齡就像我現在一樣。
Who in the year 2001 will
be the same age as I am now.
也許他會得到更好的調整，以本
什麼樣的世界，你試圖描繪的。
Maybe he will be better adjusted to this
kind of world that you're trying to portray.
最大的區別，當他長大......
The big difference, when he grows up...
事實上，如果我們想
等到2001年...
In fact, if we wanted to
wait till the year 2001...
他將在自己的房子
He will have in his own house
沒有一台電腦一樣大
此，但至少一個控制台
not a computer as big as
this, but at least a console
通過他可以跟
他友好的本地計算機
through which he can talk to
his friendly local computer
並得到所有的信息
他需要為自己的日常生活，
and get all the information
he needs for his everyday life,
喜歡他的銀行對賬單，
他的劇院的保留，
like his bank statements,
his theater reservations,
所有你需要在使用過程中的信息
生活在一個複雜的現代社會。
all the information you need in the course
of living in a complex modern society.
這將是在一個緊湊的
形成自己的房子。
This will be in a compact
form in his own house.
他將有一個電視屏幕，
像這些這裏，和一個鍵盤。
He'll have a television screen,
like these here, and a keyboard.
他會跟電腦
和從它得到的信息。
And he'll talk to the computer
and get information from it.
他將採取盡可能多的
授予我們採取了電話。
And he'll take it as much for
granted as we take the telephone.
我不知道，不過，什麼樣的
生活會是想在社會方面？
I wonder, though, what sort of a
life would it be like in social terms?
我的意思是，如果我們的整個生活
是圍繞計算機，
I mean, if our whole life
is built around the computer,
我們成為了計算機依賴的社會現象？
do we become a computer-dependent society?
在某些方面，但他們
也將豐富我們的社會
In some ways, but they
will also enrich our society
因為這將有可能使
我們的生活，真的，任何地方，我們喜歡。
because it will make it possible for
us to live, really, anywhere we like.
任何商人和行政
能夠生活在地球上幾乎任何地方
Any businessman and executive
could live almost anywhere on Earth
仍然做他的生意
通過這樣的設備。
and still do his business
through a device like this.
這是一個美妙的事情。 它的意思是
我們不會被卡在城市。
And this is a wonderful thing. It means
we won't have to be stuck in cities.
我們將能夠活出在
國家或地方，我們請。
We'll be able to live out in the
country or wherever we please.
屏幕說，這是一個
未實現的陷阱。
Screen says it's an
unimplemented trap.
但是，錯誤代碼是
錯誤。 這是一個系統錯誤。
But the error code is
wrong. It's a system error.
- 那麼，有什麼結果？
- 這不是要去打招呼
- So what's the upshot?
- It's not gonna say hello.
這絕對是要去打招呼。
It absolutely is gonna say hello.
- 這是誰的錯。 這是一個系統錯誤。
- 你建的聲音演示。
- It's nobody's fault. It's a system error.
- You built the voice demo.
- 語音演示是片狀的。
- 讓你的聲音了。
- The voice demo is flaky.
- Keep your voices down.
我一直在告訴你，
為......這件事是過度開發。
I've been telling you that
for... This thing is overbuilt.
它的工作昨晚。 它
在此之前，工作了一夜。
It worked last night. It
worked the night before that.
它的工作在三個小時以前。
It worked three hours ago.
- 這不是現在的工作，所以只跳過的聲音演示。
- 你他媽的。
- It's not working now, so just skip over the voice demo.
- Fuck you.
- 其他一切工作正常。
- 噓。
- Everything else is working.
- Shh.
跳過的聲音演示。
Skip over the voice demo.
我們需要它來打個招呼。
We need it to say hello.
- 你不聽我的。 它不會打招呼。
- 只需修復它。
- You're not hearing me. It's not going to say hello.
- Just fix it.
- 修好它？
- 是啊。
- Fix it?
- Yeah.
- 在40分鐘內？
- 修好它。
- In 40 minutes?
- Fix it.
- 我不能。
- 誰是人誰可以？
- I can't.
- Who's the person who can?
我是誰的人就可以了，我不能。
I'm the person who can, and I can't.
- 多麼糟糕，你在說什麼？
- 這是非常糟糕的。
- How bad are you saying?
- It's pretty bad.
- 我不知道這意味著什麼。
- 這意味著演示更可能會崩潰。
- I don't know what that means.
- It means the demo is more than likely gonna crash.
你必須保持你的聲音了。
You have to keep your voices down.
喬爾Pforzheimer是
坐在出在房子裏。
Joel Pforzheimer is
sitting out in the house.
我不在乎......誰是喬爾Pforzheimer？
I don't care if... Who's Joel Pforzheimer?
GQ。
GQ.
他被遮蔽你
一個星期。 你注意到了嗎？
He's been shadowing you
for a week. Did you notice?
只是看起來像一切都很好。
Just look like everything's fine.
他坐了在家裏。
He's sitting out in the house.
嘿。
Hey.
什麼是你們在說什麼？
What are you guys saying?
有些種類的競爭狀態，但我們
一直無法追蹤下來呢。
Some kind of race condition, but we
haven't been able to track it down yet.
是合成器採樣速度不夠快？
Is the synthesizer sampling fast enough?
沒有，使該利率已關閉
它總是死機。
No, so the rates are off
and it keeps crashing.
它的20個秒兩小時
發射。 為什麼不只是削減呢？
It's 20 seconds out of a two-hour
launch. Why not just cut it?
- 我們不能剪。
- 是啊，你只是削減它。
- We can't cut it.
- Yeah, you just cut it.
前兩天，我們跑了超級碗廣告的
可能已經獲得了奧斯卡最佳短片。
Two days ago, we ran a Super Bowl ad that
could've won the Oscar for Best Short Film.
還有更多的人誰可以告訴你
廣告不是可以告訴你誰贏得了比賽。
There are more people who can tell you about
the ad than can tell you who won the game.
我明白了，但廣告說：
在Mac是要去拯救世界。
I understand, but the ad said
the Mac was gonna save the world.
它並沒有說這是會打個招呼。
It didn't say it was gonna say hello.
我們在五個開放的房子。
We open the house in five.
不要打開房子。
Don't open the house.
我們正在做一項快速突破。
We're taking a quick break.
- 這個問題的部分原因是...
- 什麼？
- Part of the problem is...
- What?
我們可以重新編譯，但如果它是一個硬體
的問題，我們不能進入了。
We can recompile, but if it's a hardware
problem, we can't get into the back.
為什麼不呢？
Why not?
- 你要告訴她還是要我？
- 不要跟我做起，人。
- Do you wanna tell her or should I?
- Don't start with me, man.
- 為什麼他不能進入機器？
- 你需要特殊的工具。
- Why can't he get into the machine?
- You need special tools.
什麼樣的特殊的工具？
就拿螺絲刀。
What kind of special tools?
Just take a screwdriver.
他不想讓用戶能夠打開它。
He didn't want users to be able to open it.
你需要特殊的工具。
You need special tools.
這是真的嗎？
Is this for real?
有一百個工程師走
這周圍。 他們沒有一個有工具？
There are a hundred engineers walking
around here. None of them have the tools?
憑心而論，沒有太多的
他們發出的工具。
In fairness, not many of
them were issued the tools.
- 那你呢？
- 我離開他們的辦公室。 這是上午3:00，當我...
- What about you?
- I left them at the office. It was 3:00 AM when I...
哦，耶穌基督。
Oh, Jesus Christ.
- 切「你好。」
- 沒有。
- Cut "Hello."
- No.
- 什麼是一個推出的第一條規則？
- 這是不是會崩潰。
- What's the first rule of a launch?
- It's not gonna crash.
它只是做了。
It just did.
安迪！
Andy!
哪一個？
Which one?
其他安迪。 你是對的
那裏。 我為什麼要呼喚？
The other Andy. You're right
there. Why would I be calling out?
- 他需要和你談談。
- 是啊。
- He needs to talk to you.
- Yeah.
出口標誌必須關閉或
我們不會得到一個完整的停電。
The exit signs need to be off or
we're not gonna get a full blackout.
- 我們已經談過，樓宇管理及消防元帥。
- 和？
- We've spoken to the building manager and the fire marshal.
- And?
有沒有辦法，他們會
讓我們把出口標誌了。
There's no way they're gonna
let us turn the exit signs off.
我會付一切的罰款。
I'll pay whatever the fine is.
罰款是他們會來
並告訴大家離開。
The fine is they're gonna come
in and tell everyone to leave.
你解釋火元帥
那我們在這裏改變世界？
You explained to the fire marshal
that we're in here changing the world?
我做到了，但是除非我們也可以改變
火的性質，他並不在乎。
I did, but unless we can also change
the properties of fire, he doesn't care.
- 史蒂夫...
- 發生火災導致踩踏無人盯防的出口，
- Steve...
- If a fire causes a stampede to the unmarked exits,
它會一直很值得
這對於那些誰生存。
it'll have been well worth
it for those who survive.
對於那些誰不這樣做，少
所以，但還是相當不錯的。
For those who don't, less
so, but still pretty good.
- 你看，我...
- 我需要它走到黑。 真正的黑色。
- Look, I...
- I need it to go black. Real black.
擺脫出口標誌和
不要讓我知道你是如何做到的。
Get rid of the exit signs and
don't let me know how you did it.
修復的聲音演示。
Fix the voice demo.
您需要特殊的工具來打開Mac？
You need special tools to open the Mac?
你知道這是一個封閉的系統。
You knew it was a closed system.
我不知道從字面上。 耶穌。
I didn't know literally. Jesus.
如果你繼續這樣疏遠
人們沒有理由，
And if you keep alienating
people for no reason,
還有的會是誰
左為它打個招呼。
there's gonna be no one
left for it to say hello to.
這不是沒有理由。
It's not for no reason.
我們打​​擊這一點，IBM將擁有
未來50年如蝙蝠俠反派。
We blow this and IBM will own the
next 50 years like a Batman villain.
記住電話公司？ 那是什麼
貝爾被稱為「電話公司」。
Remember the phone company? That's what
Bell was called, "the phone company."
IBM將電腦公司。
IBM will be the computer company.
十年後，他們會
是信息的公司，
Ten years later they'll
be the information company,
而這是非常不好的人類。
and that's very bad for the human race.
因此，我們沒有時間來
禮貌還是現實，
So we don't have time to
be polite or realistic,
「因為如果我們到了，這
公司的下一個產品的推出
'cause if we are, this
company's next product launch
將在26人面前舉行
will be held in front of 26 people
並從縱梁
阿拉米達縣購物指南。
and a stringer from the
Alameda County Shopper's Guide.
我們還沒有發佈的語音軟體。
We haven't advertised the voice software.
我們可以將其拉出演示
沒有人會感到失望。
We could pull it out of the demo
and no one would be disappointed.
你想嘗試是合理的，
Do you want to try being reasonable,
只是，你知道，看看是什麼感覺？
just, you know, see what it feels like?
好。 拉的聲音演示。
Okay. Pull the voice demo.
謝謝。
Thank you.
然後取消發射。
And then cancel the launch.
我明白。 你剛才騙我一點點。
I see. You just tricked me a little.
你能告訴我這是多麼重要，
但如果電腦不打招呼，
You can tell me how unimportant it is,
but if the computer doesn't say hello,
那麼也不會約翰斯卡利，
誰我答應你同意和我在一起。
then neither will John Sculley,
who I promise you agrees with me.
斯卡利不是要取消
推出「因為他是不是瘋了。
Sculley's not gonna cancel the
launch 'cause he's not insane.
他也不是一個黑客，和
當涉及到Macintosh，
He's also not a hack, and
when it comes to the Macintosh,
他會做什麼，我問他做什麼。
he's gonna do what I ask him to do.
- 什麼是在這個盒子？
- 沒有什麼需要擔心的。
- What's in this box?
- Nothing you need to worry about.
甚至不要打開它。
Don't even open it.
什麼他媽的？
What the fuck?
為什麼會出現的紙箱......這是誰幹的？
Why is there a carton of... Who did this?
- 有人認為...
- 誰？
- Somebody thought...
- Who?
無所謂。 認為這將是一個很好的
主意，有那時間的封面複印件
Doesn't matter. Thought it would be a good
idea to have copies of that Time cover
可在每個人的座位。
available at everyone's seat.
它消滅在萌芽狀態，所有的
副本正在採取走出大樓。
It was nipped in the bud and all the
copies are being taken out of the building.
所以，問題就解決了​​。
So problem solved.
- 這不是一個Macintosh計算機。
- 我明白。
- This isn't a Macintosh.
- I understand.
有人以為它會
是個不錯的主意，比如，
Somebody thought it would
be a good idea to, like,
熱情交出的副本
時間替換封面上的一個不-A-的Macintosh
enthusiastically hand over copies of
Time with a not-a-Macintosh on the cover
在推出的Macintosh電腦的？
at the launch of the Macintosh?
什麼是他們遞過
出在惠普？
What are they handing
out at Hewlett-Packard?
蘋果與我的臉對他們的鬥？
A bushel of apples with my face on them?
我敢肯定的想法是，
因為計算機是年度人物
I'm sure the thinking was that
since the computer is Man of the Year
那這是很好的為我們的業務，
that that's good for our business,
但就像我說的，我有
他們從建築物中刪除。
but like I said, I'm having
them removed from the building.
我想請你與他們無關
就是把他們所有2600份，
What I'd like you to do with them
is to take them, all 2,600 copies,
和堆棧他們的Kottke的辦公桌
and stack them on Kottke's desk
並告訴他史蒂夫說，
「祝你新年快樂。」
and tell him Steve says,
"Happy New Year to you."
好。
Okay.
我給了時間雜誌的完全訪問權限。
I gave Time magazine full access.
整個校園：Bandley，蘋果II，麗莎。
The whole campus: Bandley, Apple II, Lisa.
我給了他斯卡利，馬庫拉。 一世
給了他沃茲。 我給他的每一個人。
I gave him Sculley, Markkula. I
gave him Woz. I gave him everybody.
我應該叫誰想到人
它會是交出這些出一個好主意嗎？
What should I call the person who thought
it'd be a good idea to hand these out?
我不會告訴你是誰。
I'm not telling you who it was.
有人做過沒有惡意。
它得到照顧。
It was done without malice.
It's been taken care of.
你有一個半小時，我們
有事情要談。
You have a half hour and we
have things to talk about.
像什麼？
Like what?
就像在頭90天百萬。
Like a million in the first 90 days.
- 喬安娜...
-  20,000個月後。
- Joanna...
- 20,000 a month after that.
- 看。 這些都是預測。
- 我求...
- Look. Those are the forecasts.
- I'm begging...
這是我的領域。 我求你
管理期望在那裏。
This is my field. I'm begging you
to manage expectations out there.
- 我煽動的期望。
- 我們不會在頭90天賣出一百萬。
- I'm fanning expectations.
- We're not gonna sell a million in the first 90 days.
每個人，每個人，每個人，
Everyone, everyone, everyone,
每個人正在等待蘋果。
everyone is waiting for the Mac.
有可能。
Maybe.
但是，會發生什麼，當他們
找出了2,495，
But what happens when they
find out that for 2,495,
還有，你可以用它做什麼？
there's nothing you can do with it?
我們為$ 1,500個有競爭力的，
We were competitive at $1,500,
但一旦你更換了
摩托羅拉6809與68000 ...
but once you replaced the
Motorola 6809 with the 68000...
這正是支持菜單，窗口，
指向和點擊，高分辨率的圖形...
Which is what supports menus, windows,
point and click, high-res graphics...
呀，因為每個人都需要
矩形帶圓角。
Yeah, 'cause everyone needs
rectangles with rounded corners.
土地教練在跑道上的
確切的同時，頭等艙。
Coach lands on the runway at the
exact same time as first class.
我沒有第一
他媽的知道這意味著什麼，
I don't have the first
fucking idea what that means,
但是這是怎麼得$ 2,500
but this is how it got to $2,500,
這是對價格點
PC機，它可以做更多的事情！
which is the price point on
the PC, which can do a lot more!
誰的會想要一台PC？
什麼白癡是要去想...
Who's gonna want a PC?
What idiot is gonna want...
如果我想告訴你有一個點
在你的襯衫，我點到現場。
If I wanna tell you there's a spot
on your shirt, I point to the spot.
我不說有一個點14
從衣領厘米下來
I don't say there's a spot 14
centimeters down from the collar
三厘米到的
右邊的第二個按鈕
and three centimeters to the
right of the second button
當我試圖記住什麼
該命令對蘇打水。
while I try to remember what
the command is for club soda.
這不是一個人如何的心靈的作品。
That's not how a person's mind works.
如果目標是便於使用，也許
你應該已經給它一些內存。
If the goal was ease of use, maybe
you should've given it some memory.
你可以抱怨內存
或者你可以抱怨的價格，
You can complain about memory
or you can complain about price,
但你不能同時做到這兩點。
but you can't do both at the same time.
內存是要花錢的。
Memory is what costs money.
我很高興你告訴我
您對Mac的現在的心情
I'm glad you're telling me
your feelings about the Mac now
因為我們有一個半小時離開。
because we have a half hour left.
我們可以重新設計它。
We can redesign it.
我只是要求你管理的期望。
I'm just asking you to manage expectations.
看看他們的臉
當他們看到它是什麼。
Look at their faces
when they see what it is.
他們不知道自己在做什麼
看著或者他們為什麼喜歡它，
They won't know what they're
looking at or why they like it,
但他們會知道他們想要的。
but they'll know they want it.
不是瞬間。 當人們
聽到春之祭，
Not instantly. When people
heard Rite of Spring,
他們撕毀椅子走出影院。
they tore the chairs out of the theater.
他們沒有購買記錄。
They didn't buy the record.
春之祭的情況
是最革命性
Rite of Spring happens
to be the most revolutionary
和挑釁性的交響樂
上個世紀。
and provocative symphony
of the last century.
芭蕾舞。 這是一個芭蕾舞。
Ballet. It was a ballet.
但斯特拉文斯基並沒有說他
要去一個月銷售20000台。
But Igor Stravinsky didn't say he
was gonna sell 20,000 units a month.
我不知道為什麼我們
談論斯特拉文斯基
I don't know why we're
talking about Stravinsky
當我關心的是丹科特肯
雞姦我在時間雜誌。
when what I care about is Dan Kottke
sodomizing me in Time magazine.
看。 明顯...
Look. Obviously...
讓我這樣說你。
Let me say this to you.
顯然，丹尼爾沒有想到
他在做什麼錯。
Obviously, Daniel didn't think
he was doing anything wrong.
- 通過交談，時間的呢？
- 是啊。
- By talking to Time about it?
- Yeah.
我不知道這意味著什麼。
I don't know what that means.
你說，當你告訴我的故事...
You said, when you told me the story...
你說你到丹說，
You said you said to Dan,
「難道時間的雜誌問你
如果我有一個名為麗莎的女兒嗎？「
"Did Time magazine ask you
if I had a daughter named Lisa?"
而丹說，「是啊。」
And Dan said, "Yeah."
我的意思是，他回答
你只需和誠實
My point was that he answered
you simply and honestly
因為他不認為
他做任何事。
because he didn't think
he'd done anything wrong.
除非，喬安娜......除了我
沒有一個叫麗莎的女兒。
Except, Joanna... Except I
don't have a daughter named Lisa.
而這個故事現在大概我是如何
拒絕親子鑒定，並採取了驗血。
And this story is now about how I'm
denying paternity and took a blood test.
這就是為什麼有一個圖片...
我不知道他媽的這是什麼。
And that's why there's a picture of...
I don't know what the fuck that is.
這就是為什麼有一個
在封面上的PC機圖片
That's why there's a
picture of a PC on the cover
代替我和Mac的圖片。
instead of a picture of me and the Mac.
我不知道該怎麼告訴你。
I don't know what to tell you.
我應該是時間
雜誌的年度人物。
I was supposed to be Time
magazine's Man of the Year.
然後丹Kottke的誕生。
And then Dan Kottke was born.
- 井...
- 什麼？
- Well...
- What?
- 她在等待著你。
- 誰？
- She's waiting for you.
- Who?
-  Chrisann。
- 布倫南？
- Chrisann.
- Brennan?
他們在大廳裏。
They're out in the hall.
他們已經坐在後面
因為7:00今天早上的禮堂。
They've been sitting in the back of
the auditorium since 7:00 this morning.
我並沒有把會話
與Chrisann現在。
I'm not having a session
with Chrisann right now.
我們發出335新聞
憑據推出。
We issued 335 press
credentials for the launch.
史蒂夫，你激怒Chrisann，
Steve, you piss off Chrisann,
她傻傻的站在了
遊說，並給335的採訪，
she's gonna stand in the
lobby and give 335 interviews,
而你，夥計，會嚮往
太平日子丹的Kottke的。
and you, pal, will be longing for
the halcyon days of Dan Kottke.
讓我結束這。
Let me get this over with.
但是，不要離開。 你會留在這兒。
But don't leave. You're gonna stay here.
什麼？ 不，我不是。
What? No. I'm not.
號有較少的一個機會
現場，如果你留在這兒。 她會很酷。
No. There's less of a chance of a
scene if you stay here. She'll be cool.
我覺得這一切難以忍受
個人及-和...
I find all this excruciatingly
personal and-and...
我 - 我......我不能呆在這。
I-I'm... I'm not staying.
第來吧。
No. Come on.
我並不想成為一個
房間單獨與Chrisann。
I don't wanna be in a
room alone with Chrisann.
這是我和你。
This is me and you.
精細。
Fine.
嘿。
Hey.
史蒂夫。
Steve.
這是一個驚喜。
This is a surprise.
在你為什麼不來呢？
Why don't you come on in?
謝謝。
Thank you.
- 你來了嗎？
- 是的，我不會離開她在走廊上。
- You coming too?
- Yes, I'm not gonna leave her in the hallway.
好。 這是一個安全走廊，但無論如何。
Okay. It's a safe hallway, but anyway.
你還記得喬安娜·霍夫曼？ 她
市場部主管為Mac。
You remember Joanna Hoffman? She's
the head of marketing for the Mac.
很高興見到你。
Good to see you.
很高興見到你。 你好，麗莎。
Nice to see you. Hello, Lisa.
我們以前見過的，你告訴
我你喜歡我說話的方式，
We've met before, and you told
me you like the way I talk,
那是我最喜歡的
事情任何人的以往任何時候都對我說。
and that was my favorite
thing anyone's ever said to me.
- 你是來自波蘭。
- 對，我是。
- You're from Poland.
- Yes, I am.
- 你知道那是什麼？
- 地球的頂部。
- Do you know where that is?
- The top of the Earth.
我想，你在想北極。
I think you're thinking of the North Pole.
好了，我們有點
時間緊迫，所以...
Well, we're a little
pressed for time, so...
- 我會離開你們一個人。
- 為什麼你想離開的時候，你剛才說的...
- I'll leave you guys alone.
- Why do you wanna leave when you just said...
我要去檢查與赫茨菲爾德。
I'm gonna check in with Hertzfeld.
我們正在試圖獲得一個
電腦打個招呼，
We're trying to get a
computer to say hello,
但現在它是非常害羞。
but right now it's being very shy.
你會不會幫助我嗎？ 可以嗎？
Would you come help me? Is that okay?
當然。
Sure.
謝謝。
Thank you.
我爸我的名字命名的計算機。
My dad named a computer after me.
我不是你的......
I'm not your...
其實，你知道是什麼
巧合的是，麗莎？
Actually, do you know what
a coincidence is, Lisa?
沒有。
No.
就像如果你遇到了什麼人。
Like if you met someone.
你犯了一個新朋友
她的名字叫麗莎了。
You made a new friend
and her name was Lisa too.
這將是一個巧合。
That would be a coincidence.
「麗莎」的全稱是「本地
集成系統架構「。
"Lisa" stands for "Local
Integrated Systems Architecture."
L-I-S-A。
L-I-S-A.
這是一個巧合。
It's a coincidence.
- 你大概做了什麼？
- 是啊。
- You about done?
- Yeah.
好。
Okay.
來。 讓我們的電腦打招呼。
Come. Let's make that computer say hi.
來吧，麗莎。
Go ahead, Lisa.
所以這是周圍的其他方法。
So it was the other way around.
我被評為計算機後？
I was named after the computer?
沒有被命名後，
任何人。 這是一個巧合。
Nothing was named after
anybody. It's a coincidence.
加油。
Come on.
你到底是怎麼回事？
What's the matter with you?
你到底是怎麼回事？ 為什麼
你要告訴她這事嗎？
What's the matter with you? Why
are you telling her these things?
為什麼你還告訴
她我是她的父親嗎？
Why are you still telling
her I'm her father?
- 法官告訴她，你是她的父親。
- 不，他沒有。
- A judge told her you're her father.
- No, he didn't.
當你到底下車
告訴時間雜誌
Where the hell do you get off
telling Time magazine
我已經睡了28％
的男子在美國？
I've slept with 28 percent
of the men in America?
- 這不是...
- 你在哪裏下車？
- That's not...
- Where do you get off?
這不是遠程我說。
That's not remotely what I said.
就是這裏。
It's right here.
首先，我可以告訴你
一些關於時間的雜誌？
First of all, can I tell you
something about Time magazine?
我相信這是一個培訓
設施支付的刺客。
I believe it's a training
facility for paid assassins.
- 「喬布斯堅持」...我引用...
- 我沒有發明的數學。
- "Jobs insists"... I am quoting...
- I didn't invent math.
的「28％的
男性人口美國
"twenty-eight percent of the
male population of the United States
可能是爸爸。「
could be the father."
我不是說你睡
隨著美國男性28％。
I wasn't saying you've slept
with 28% of American men.
我使用的算法
基於該血液檢查
I was using an algorithm
based on the blood test
它說，有94.1％
的機會，我的父親。
which said there was a 94.1%
chance that I'm the father.
你試圖公開
把我描述成一個蕩婦和妓女。
You're trying to publicly
paint me as a slut and a whore.
相信我，我不是要
公開做你任何東西。
Believe me, I'm not trying to
publicly do anything with you.
兩百萬人閱讀
時間。我怎麼...
Two million people read
Time. How am I supposed...
這將是更多，如果他們把我的封面上，
但丹科特肯決定以腎虛衝我...
It would be more if they put me on the cover,
but Dan Kottke decided to kidney-punch me...
- 我昨天申請了福利。
- 對不起？
- I applied for welfare yesterday.
- I'm sorry?
- 您好！
- 我說我昨天申請福利。
- Hello!
- I said I applied for welfare yesterday.
在時間的文章稱您
蘋果股票是價值$ 441億美元，
The Time article said your
Apple stock was worth $441 million,
我想問你
你怎麼感覺有關。
and I wanted to ask you
how you felt about that.
好吧，我覺得蘋果股票
已被嚴重低估。
Well, I feel like Apple stock
has been dramatically undervalued.
這將是一個很好的時間去研究。
This would be a good time to get in.
你的女兒和她的母親......
Your daughter and her mother...
-  Chrisann ...
- 是的福利。
- Chrisann...
- are on welfare.
我們住在門洛帕克一個小屋。
We're living in a hovel in Menlo Park.
我們不能支付取暖費。
We can't pay the heating bills.
她睡在一個大衣。
She sleeps in a parka.
- 您的女兒......
- 她不是我的女兒！
- Your daughter...
- She's not my daughter!
因為，據報道
按時間的雜誌，
Because, as reported
by Time magazine,
- 我已經睡了的人在美國，28％？
- 沒有。
- I've slept with 28% of the men in America?
- No.
所有這些，恰恰就是個
麗莎的前幾個月就誕生了。
All of them, exactly nine
months before Lisa was born.
我有安迪在這裏。
I've got Andy here.
打擾一下。
Excuse me.
在那裏？
We're there?
- 嘿，克裏斯。
- 嘿，安迪。
- Hey, Chris.
- Hey, Andy.
- 你最近怎樣'？
- 可怕。
- How are you doin'?
- Terrible.
你們趕上了嗎？
You guys caught up now?
請原諒我說一下我的
朋友，誰認為你是一個傢伙。
Excuse me for saying hello to my
friend, who thinks you're a dick.
- 我不認為你是一個...
- 在那裏？
- I don't think you're a...
- We're there?
- 號它有一在六個機會的工作。
- 他媽的。
- No. It's got a one-in-six chance of working.
- Goddamn it.
那麼，我們是不是一個維修人員在Daytona。
這不能被固定在秒。
Well, we're not a pit crew at Daytona.
This can't be fixed in seconds.
你沒有秒。
你有三個星期。
You didn't have seconds.
You had three weeks.
被創造宇宙
在那段時間的三分之一。
The universe was created
in a third of that time.
好了，有一天你會擁有
告訴我們你是怎麼做的。
Well, someday you'll have
to tell us how you did it.
下面是我該怎麼辦。
Here's what I'm gonna do.
我要宣佈的名字
大家誰設計了發射演示。
I'm gonna announce the names of
everyone who designed the launch demo.
我要介紹給大家
並要求他們站起來。
I'm gonna introduce everyone
and ask them to stand up.
該袋是由蘇珊·卡蕾設計。
The bag was designed by Susan Kare.
在Macintosh字體多數民眾贊成在整個滾動
屏幕由史蒂夫·卡普斯設計。
The Macintosh font that's scrolling across
the screen was designed by Steve Capps.
星夜和
空中文字是布魯斯·霍恩。
The starry night and
skywriting was Bruce Horn.
MacPaint格式，MacWrite，愛麗絲，
下到計算器。
MacPaint, MacWrite, Alice,
down to the calculator.
然後我會說，
語音演示，沒有工作
And then I'm gonna say the
voice demo that didn't work
由安迪·赫茲菲爾德設計的。
was designed by Andy Hertzfeld.
史蒂夫...
Steve...
五在六個是你生存的機會
第一輪俄羅斯輪盤賭的，
Five-in-six is your chance of surviving
the first round of Russian roulette,
你已經逆轉的可能性。
and you've reversed those odds.
所以，除非你想被蒙羞
在你的朋友面前，
So unless you wanna be disgraced
in front of your friends,
家人，同事，
股東和媒體，
family, colleagues,
stockholders and the press,
我就不會站在這裏爭論。
I wouldn't stand here arguing.
我會去嘗試，並得到一些
更多的子彈從槍。
I'd go try and get some
more bullets out of the gun.
做到這一點，安迪！
Do it, Andy!
停止。 您。
Stop. You.
- 你穿幾號球衣？
- 我？
- What size shirt do you wear?
- Me?
有誰知道什麼尺寸的襯衫
他穿？ 我穿什麼尺寸的襯衫嗎？
Does anyone know what size shirt
he wears? What size shirt I wear?
有誰知道在哪裏
最近的心理醫生是？
Does anyone know where the
closest psychiatrist is?
在你的口袋磁盤適合。
The disk fits in your pocket.
我需要一個襯衫搭配乳房
口袋。 我可以把它拿出來在舞台上。
I need a shirt with a breast
pocket. I can take it out onstage.
- 襯衫？
- 磁盤！
- A shirt?
- The disk!
我需要一件白襯衫在我
大小與一個胸前的口袋。
I need a white shirt in my
size with a breast pocket.
是。 其中無一
多家店，在8:45開
Yes. Which one of the no
stores that are open at 8:45
你想我有一個人跑
往返在15分鐘內返回？
do you want me to have someone run
to and return from in 15 minutes?
走出大廳，找人
我的尺寸是誰穿著白襯衫。
Go out in the lobby, find someone
my size who's wearing a white shirt.
告訴他們，我會換
他們為免費電腦，
Tell them I'll trade
them for a free computer,
而他們得到保持我的襯衫。
and they get to keep my shirt.
它必須是一個
白襯衫？ 是藍色的好嗎？
Does it have to be a
white shirt? Is blue okay?
號的Mac是米色的，我是米黃色的
磁盤是藍色的，襯衫具有為白色。
No. The Mac is beige, I'm beige, the
disk is blue, the shirt has to be white.
安迪？
Andy?
你好，我是Macintosh電腦。
Hello, I'm Macintosh.
給我安迪·赫茲菲爾德的頭。
Bring me the head of Andy Hertzfeld.
我試圖得到它
打個招呼，但它是害羞。
I tried to get it to
say hello, but it's shy.
是啊。
Yeah.
所以這是它？
So that's it?
而已。
That's it.
我不明白這一點。
I don't get it.
我知道。
I know.
人們在打算怎麼辦呢？
What are people going to do with it?
麗莎，你幾歲了？
Lisa, how old are you now?
- 你知道她是多麼的老了。
- 你多大了，麗莎？
- You know how old she is.
- How old are you, Lisa?
五。
Five.
來這裏坐一分鐘。
Come sit here for a minute.
你知道這是什麼？
Do you know what this is?
- 這是一台電腦。
- It's a computer.
我能借你的手一秒鐘？
Can I borrow your hand for a second?
點箭頭，然後單擊。
Point that arrow and click.
你沒有，但如果你
想要的，你可以用它玩。
You don't have to, but if you
want, you can play with it.
沒有什麼可以做會打破它，
所以只是做任何你想做的事情。
Nothing you can do will break it,
so just do whatever you want with it.
你在做什麼？
What are you doing?
我付你到底是什麼
法院命令我給你錢了。
I'm paying you exactly what
the court ordered me to pay you.
$ 385一個月。
$385 a month.
我不是一個誰決定的金額。
I'm not the one who decided on that amount.
而我要問你，你的感覺如何。
And I'm asking you how you feel.
如果你覺得沒事。
If you feel all right.
- 如果感覺沒事了你，你的女兒......
- 她不是我的......
- If it feels all right to you that your daughter...
- She's not my...
那你的女兒和
她的母親是福利
That your daughter and
her mother are on welfare
當你的價值$ 441
千萬製作的。
while you're worth $441
million for making that.
我很自豪地說，蘋果公司捐贈
計算機資金不足的學校，
I'm proud to say Apple donates
computers to underfunded schools,
- 我們會做更多同樣與Mac ...
- 什麼？
- and we'll be doing more of the same with the Mac...
- What?
蘋果公司捐贈了數百萬美元「
值得一電腦學校。
Apple donates millions of dollars'
worth of computers to schools.
什麼叫有什麼關係？
What does that have to do with...
想像一下，一個貧困的孩子，有
24小時自己喜歡的老師他們。
Imagine an underprivileged kid that has
their favorite teacher with them 24 hours.
我們是幾分鐘的路程從
能夠做到這一點。
We're minutes away from
being able to do that.
在你的頭上，是
回答我的問題？
In your head, was that
an answer to my question?
再次告訴我這個問題。
Tell me the question again.
我不是誰起訴一
您的子女撫養費。
I wasn't the one who sued
you for child support.
- 不，讓...
- 聖馬刁縣起訴你。
- No, let...
- San Mateo County sued you.
不，讓我解釋發生了什麼，
「因為我有足夠的時間現在。
No, let me explain what happened,
'cause I have plenty of time right now.
打擾一下。 你有訪客。
Excuse me. You have a visitor.
只想說好
運氣。 嘿，Chrisann。
Just wanted to say good
luck. Hey, Chrisann.
- 你好，沃茲。
- 不掛斷。
- Hello, Woz.
- Hang on.
- 只想說好運氣。
- 謝謝。 你也是。
- Just wanted to say good luck.
- Thanks. You too.
- 這是一個很大的早晨。
- 是啊。
- It's a big morning.
- Yeah.
你應該可以看到這個人群那裏。
You should see this crowd out there.
這個人群，就好像，嗯...
This crowd, it's like, um...
我真的不能等你來
拿出一個比喻，人。
I can't really wait for you to
come up with a metaphor, man.
- 是啊。 所以，聽著，我想請你幫個忙。
- 是啊？
- Yeah. So, listen, I want to ask you a favor.
- Yeah?
- 你可以確認的Apple II團隊在你說的話？
- 我不能。
- Can you acknowledge the Apple II team in your remarks?
- I cannot.
只是一個確認。
Just an acknowledgement.
讓他們站起來。
Have them stand up.
- 我們推出了Mac。
- 這將會是一個鼓舞士氣。
- We're launching the Mac.
- It'd be a morale booster.
只要一提起這樣他們就可以
獲得一片掌聲。
Just a mention so they could
get a round of applause.
- 只需一提。
- 我們能否堅持一個引腳採用了一分鐘？
- Just a mention.
- Can we stick a pin in this for a minute?
- 當然。
- 謝謝。
- Sure.
- Thank you.
剛才談的是
確認為球隊。
Just talking about an
acknowledgement for the team.
我有Chrisann在那裏。
我會看到你在一秒鐘。
I've got Chrisann in there.
I'll see you in a second.
是的。
Yep.
那。
That.
什麼？
What?
你問我是什麼人，因為我的
用它做。 他們會做到這一點。
You asked me what people are gonna
do with it. They're gonna do that.
其中一名工程師。
One of the engineers.
謝謝。
Thank you.
你喜歡它嗎？
Do you like it?
對不起？
I'm sorry?
這是一個抽像的。
It's an abstract.
你用MacPaint格式。
You used MacPaint.
推同時該鍵以及「S」。
Push that key and the "S" at the same time.
現在，輸入您的姓名。
Now type your name.
你知道哪個箱子說：「保存」？
Do you know which box says "Save"?
對。 來吧，一下就可以了。
Right. Go ahead and click on it.
我會把一些錢在您的帳戶
I'll put some money in your account
並給你買了新房子，
附近某處一個像樣的學校。
and buy you a new house,
someplace near a decent school.
謝謝。
Thank you.
沃茲想一分鐘。
Woz wants a minute.
而斯卡利的找你。
And Sculley's asking for you.
做完了？
We're done?
你能教我更多的東西？
Could you teach me more things?
在電腦上面？
On the computer?
麗莎，等我在大廳裏，請。
Lisa, wait for me in the hall, please.
你可以把你的大衣在大廳裏。
You can put your coat on in the hall.
再見，麗莎。
Bye, Lisa.
- 再見。
- 麗莎，在大廳裏。 現在。
- Bye.
- Lisa, in the hall. Now.
我想知道，當你說你是
要去把錢存在我的賬戶，
I wanna know, when you say you're
gonna put money in my account,
我們有多少談。
how much we're talking about.
這是一所學校的一天。 她
需要在學校。
It's a school day. She
needs to be in school.
我會給你任何你所需要的。
I'm gonna give you whatever you need.
沃茲要我承認
蘋果II團隊。
Woz wants me to acknowledge
the Apple II team.
你必須能夠看到
她看起來像你。
You must be able to see
that she looks like you.
我不想侮辱沃茲。 一世
只是覺得它是向後看
I don't want to insult Woz. I
just think it's backward-looking
恰好在錯誤的時刻。
at exactly the wrong moment.
- 我知道你聽到我說的話。
- 我聽到你說的話，喬安娜。
- I know you heard what I said.
- I heard what you said, Joanna.
這只是我們即將做這件事情。
It's just we're about to do this thing.
在9:41，這個星球上會轉變
其軸線近了，永遠。
At 9:41, the planet's gonna shift
on its axis nigh and forever.
兩個最顯著
20世紀的事件：
Two most significant
events of the 20th century:
盟軍贏得戰爭的勝利，這。
The Allies win the war and this.
本。
This.
因此，也許現在是不
最好的時候罵我
So maybe right now isn't the
very best time to scold me
不成為一個更好的父親
一個孩子誰不是我的孩子。
for not being a better father
to a kid who's not my kid.
- 測試說我...
- 我不在乎測試所說的話。
- The test said I...
- I don't care what the test said.
我不關心94.1％
I don't care about 94.1%
或者你用瘋狂算法
去的美國男性28％。
or the insane algorithm you used
to get to 28% of American men.
她買了新房子。
我給她錢。
Buying her a new house.
I'm giving her money.
有一個小女孩誰
相信你是她的父親。
There's a small girl who
believes you're her father.
就這樣。 這是所有的數學存在。
That's all. That's all the math there is.
她認為它。 什麼是
你打算怎麼辦呢？
She believes it. What are
you gonna do about that?
上帝派他唯一的兒子在一自殺任務，
God sent his only son on a suicide mission,
但我們喜歡他呢
因為他做了樹木。
but we like him anyway
because he made trees.
我們要賣出一百萬
單元中的第一個90天。
We're gonna sell a million
units in the first 90 days.
20000一個月後。
20,000 a month after that.
因此，也許你可以給
我休息一下，霍夫曼女士？
So maybe you could give
me a break, Ms. Hoffman?
- 沃茲。
- 嘿。
- Woz.
- Hey.
有沒有在該自動售貨機
機器不會殺你。
There's nothing in that vending
machine that won't kill you.
- 只是瀏覽。
- 讓我們出去走走。
- Just browsing.
- Let's take a walk.
- 我能告訴你一些事嗎？
- 是啊。
- Can I tell you something?
- Yeah.
在毛伊島，蘋果會後
二隊感到不滿和憤怒和向下。
After the meeting in Maui, the Apple
II team was upset and angry and down.
- 你知道為什麼嗎？
- 由於蘋果II中沒有提到甚至一度？
- Do you know why?
- Because the Apple II wasn't mentioned even once?
蘋果II並沒有提及電動汽車...
The Apple II wasn't mentioned ev...
對，就是那樣。 你擁有了它。 是。
Yes, that's it. You have it. Yes.
- 這不是一個疏忽。
- 他們知道這一點。 他們知道事實並非如此。
- That wasn't an oversight.
- They know that. They know it wasn't.
我不想做一個
大不了出這...
I don't wanna make a
big deal out of this...
這完全是你的能力範圍內。
That's entirely within your power.
- 蘋果II是...
- 蘋果II是什麼，朋友。
- The Apple II is...
- The Apple II is what was, my friend.
蘋果II是支付帳單
在這裏，擁有七年。
The Apple II is what pays the bills
around here and has for seven years.
如果你為難這些人，
And if you embarrass these people,
你會看到一個大腦
漏在這家公司，我的兄弟。
you are going to see a brain
drain at this company, my brother.
馬庫拉帶你離開麗莎，不
他們，而不是我，所以不怪？
Markkula took you off the Lisa, not
them and not me, so don't blame...
馬庫拉了，因為我從他的麗莎
強烈的宗教反對使它好。
Markkula took me off the Lisa because of his
strong religious objection to making it good.
現在我給你的一切
你想在Apple II。
Now I gave you everything
you wanted on the Apple II.
你不要問了很多？
You don't ask for a lot?
有沒有一個單一的戰鬥，你失去了。
There wasn't a single fight you lost.
你承認的插槽中
原因是蘋果II的成功？
Do you concede the slots are the
reason for the success of the Apple II?
- 我們不能仍然是談論插槽。
- 我有一個點。
- We can't still be talking about the slots.
- I have a point.
它已經七年。 你還是
正在做。 你在談論的插槽。
It's been seven years. You're still
doing it. You're talking about the slots.
有些事你錯了。
這種說法開始在車庫裏。
There's something wrong with you.
This argument started in the garage.
你在說什麼？ 為什麼
你會只想要兩​​個插槽？
What are you talking about? Why
would you only want two slots?
打印機和調製解調器。
A printer and a modem.
8個插槽，你...
With eight slots, you...
這是一個巨大的交易，我們
能夠增加8插槽。
This is a huge deal that we
were able to add eight slots.
我很欣賞的工程，
但它不是我們在做什麼。
I appreciate the engineering,
but it's not what we're doing.
- 感謝上帝我贏了這樣的說法？
- 沃茲。
- And thank God I won that argument...
- Woz.
由於開放系統是什麼
人們喜歡的機器，
Because the open system is what
people love about the machine,
它就是為什麼它出售，仍然銷售。
and it's why it sold and still sells.
一個開放的系統。 我們
不是做一個開放的系統。
An open system. We're
not doing an open system.
當然我們。 這就是人們想要什麼，
和蘋果II的突破...
Of course we are. That's what people want,
and the breakthrough on the Apple II...
人們不知道他們
想直到你展示給他們。
People don't know what they
want until you show it to them.
嚴重的用戶想要自定義。 他們
想修改。 他們想托住它。
Serious users want to customize. They
wanna modify. They wanna jack it up.
他們希望硬體工程師一樣
我以擴展其性能，好嗎？
They want hardware engineers like
me to expand its capabilities, okay?
鍵盤音樂，更好的音板，
Keyboards for music, better sound board,
更好的顯示板，
改進的內存卡。
better display boards,
improved memory cards.
而這就是為什麼有
3000人在這裏現在。
And it's why there are
3,000 people here right now.
槽是什麼讓蘋果II
跑，只是一個例子，VisiCalc的，
The slots are what allowed the Apple II
to run, for just one example, VisiCalc,
從我的猜測一手賣
20萬和30萬的機器。
which from my guess single-handedly sold
between 200,000 and 300,000 machines.
- 他們想插槽。
- 他們沒有得到一票。
- They want slots.
- They don't get a vote.
當迪倫寫的「擋風遮雨，」他
沒有要求人們作出貢獻的歌詞。
When Dylan wrote "Shelter from the Storm," he
didn't ask people to contribute to the lyrics.
戲劇不停止這樣的
劇作家可以問觀眾
Plays don't stop so the
playwright can ask the audience
他們會是什麼景象希望看到下一個。
what scene they'd like to see next.
- 畫家...
- 愛好者...
- Painters...
- Hobbyists...
我們瀕臨
一個構造...愛好者？
We're on the verge of
a tectonic... Hobbyists?
打印機和調製解調器。 兩個插槽。
A printer and a modem. Two slots.
蘋果II球隊有我的感情，
The Apple II team has my affection,
但我不愛了七年之久
產品在蘋果推出。
but I'm not loving up a seven-year-old
product at the Mac launch.
- 電腦是不是畫。
- 你他媽的。
- Computers aren't paintings.
- Fuck you.
我會說，每次「你他媽的」你
說，直到你死亡或者停止。
I'm gonna say "fuck you" every time you
say that until you either die or stop.
- 史蒂夫...
- 嘗試一下。
- Steve...
- Try it.
- 史蒂夫。
- 說出來。
- Steve.
- Say it.
- 電腦是不是畫。
- 你他媽的。
- Computers aren't paintings.
- Fuck you.
是的，他們是些什麼人
我要的是一個封閉的系統。
Yes, they are, and what
I want is a closed system.
端至端的控制。 全然
有什麼不兼容。
End-to-end control. Completely
incompatible with anything.
計算機是不應該
有人類的缺陷。
Computers aren't supposed
to have human flaws.
我不打算建立這個與你。
I'm not going to build this one with yours.
史蒂夫！
Steve!
嘿。
Hey.
今天是關於Macintosh電腦。
和Mac是我的。
Today is about the Macintosh.
And the Mac is mine.
- 我給你的。
- 謝謝。
- I give you that.
- Thank you.
我給你說。 剛剛公開
承認蘋果II團隊
I give you that. Just publicly
acknowledge the Apple II team
「因為這是正確的事情。
'cause it's the right thing to do.
我們就會知道很快，如果你是
達芬奇或只是想你，
We'll know soon enough if you are
Leonardo da Vinci or just think you are,
但在此期間，這將是巨大的...
but in the meantime, it would be great...
在此期間，蘋果II完成。
In the meantime, the Apple II is done.
七年。 這是一個偉大的運行。
Seven years. It was a great run.
你應該出門
房子和你坐下。
You should go out in the
house and take your seat.
Mac的是傑夫·拉斯金的。
The Mac is Jef Raskin's.
說出來對我來說。
Say it for me.
- 電腦是不是...
- 你他媽的。
- Computers aren't...
- Fuck you.
好吧。
All right.
五，六...
Five, six...
- 在那裏？
- 我需要更多的時間。
- We're there?
- I need more time.
- 你不能擁有它。
- 20分鐘。
- You can't have it.
- 20 minutes.
- 這是8:58。
- 我們可以起步較晚。
- It's 8:58.
- We can start late.
聽我說。 我們是一家電腦
公司。 我們不能起步較晚。
Hear me. We're a computer
company. We can't start late.
- 然後，我有另一種想法。
- 什麼？
- Then I have another idea.
- What?
它的欺騙性和邊緣是不道德的。
It's deceptive and borderline unethical.
- 我在聽。
- 它會運行在512。
- I'm listening.
- It'll run on the 512.
- 你測試它？
- 是啊。
- You tested it?
- Yeah.
- 等待。 你要去演示128計算機上的512？
- 沒有人會知道。
- Wait. You're gonna demo a 128 computer on a 512?
- Nobody's gonna know.
你認為這是
邊界不道德？
And you think that's
borderline unethical?
名字我其他的選擇，請。
Name my other choices, please.
請。 你得告訴我，為什麼它
所以重要的是它打招呼。
Please. You have to tell me why it's
so important for it to say hello.
好萊塢。 他們做
計算機可怕的事情。
Hollywood. They made
computers scary things.
看到這讓我想起了一個友好的你
臉，磁盤插槽是一個愚蠢的笑容？
See how this reminds you of a friendly
face, that the disk slot is a goofy grin?
它的溫暖，它的俏皮
它需要打個招呼。
It's warm and it's playful
and it needs to say hello.
它需要打個招呼，因為它可以。
It needs to say hello because it can.
我們沒有實施欺詐。
We're not committing fraud.
512是要去船在不到一年。
The 512 is gonna ship in under a year.
你會免除我你
東歐的不滿？
Will you absolve me of your
Eastern European disapproval?
在計算機 2001年的打了個招呼所有的時間
它仍然嚇死我了。
The computer in 2001 said hello all the time
and it still scared the shit out of me.
赦免我。
Absolve me.
就為了這個。
Just for this.
而就在現在。
And just for now.
女士們，先生們，請歡迎
創始董事會成員邁克·馬庫拉。
Ladies and gentlemen, please welcome
founding board member Mike Markkula.
好吧。 好。
All right. Okay.
去使宇宙，史蒂芬凹痕。
Go make a dent in the universe, Steven.
看到你在一兩個小時。
See you in a couple hours.
而且我要帶我們走過
本次會議的正式部分，
And I'm going to take us through
the formal part of the meeting,
法律的一部分，如果你願意。
the legal part, if you will.
感謝仁慈的上帝。 騎兵真實體現出來。
Thank merciful God. The cavalry's shown up.
我聽說你已經比平時這更糟糕
早上。 我不認為這是可能的。
I hear you've been worse than usual this
morning. I didn't think that was possible.
所以我一直派遣
作為「史蒂夫語。」
So I've been dispatched
as the "Steve Whisperer."
這是1955年瑪歌。
This is a '55 Margaux.
- 這是在早上9:00。
- 這是一個1955年瑪歌。
- It's 9:00 in the morning.
- This is a '55 Margaux.
這是我的想像或已
你開始穿衣服喜歡我？
Is it my imagination or have
you started to dress like me?
這是一個壞主意，有馬庫拉
與季報打開。
It was a bad idea to have Markkula
open with quarterly reports.
相反，我們應該有剛
對觀眾落雨。
Instead we should have just
dropped water on the audience.
你知道的，只是大10000加侖的油箱
的冷水，從天花板丟棄。
You know, just big 10,000-gallon tanks
of cold water, dropped from the ceiling.
邁克保存一些錢索引卡片。
Save Mike some money on index cards.
- 哦，只是放鬆。
- 為什麼？
- Oh, just relax.
- Why?
我不知道。 沒人
曾經問我這個問題。
I don't know. No one's
ever asked me that question.
你去那裏。
There you go.
你是唯一一個誰看
世界以同樣的方式我這樣做。
You're the only one who sees
the world the same way I do.
沒有人看到的世界，你做同樣的方式。
No one sees the world the same way you do.
我就像凱撒大帝，約翰。
I'm like Julius Caesar, John.
- 我被敵人包圍。
- 不你不是。
- I'm surrounded by enemies.
- No, you're not.
- 板子...
- 哦，董事會。 董事會的在你身後。
- The board...
- Oh, the board. The board's behind you.
只是因為你看到它他們。
Only because you see to it they are.
我認為這是一個良好的電路板，
I think it's a good board,
但如果你要我推他們出去
一個接一個，我們可以談論這一點。
but if you want me to push them out
one by one, we can talk about that.
我希望你把他們均是在一次...
I want you to push them out all at once...
通過一個窗口，如果它是最近的出口。
through a window, if it's the nearest exit.
他們臉上的表情
當我們發現他們的地方。
The look on their faces
when we showed them the spot.
我看不到他們的臉，「因為他們
在表上敲打他們的頭。
I couldn't see their faces, 'cause they
were banging their heads on the table.
是啊。 昨天，
一天後播出的一次，
Yeah, yeah. Yesterday, the
day after it airs once,
的廣告週刊的通話發行
它有史以來最好的廣告。
the publisher of Adweek calls
it the best commercial of all time.
！所有的時間 它是。
Of all time! And it is.
如果有人做的更好，這會是
Chiat / Day公司，誰是董事會希望更換，
And if anyone does one better, it's gonna be
Chiat/Day, who the board wanted to replace,
它會是李克勞，誰的
董事會認為是出了主意。
and it's gonna be Lee Clow, who the
board thought was out of his mind.
女士們，先生們，「1984年。」
Ladies and gentlemen, "1984."
第一個輝煌週年
The first glorious anniversary
信息
淨化指令。​​
of the information
purification directives.
我們已經為創建
第一次在所有歷史
We have created for the
first time in all history
純意識形態的花園
a garden of pure ideology
每一個勞動者可以開花，
where each worker may bloom,
從purveying害蟲安全
矛盾的思想。
secure from the pests purveying
contradictory thoughts.
我們的思想統一是更強大
武器比在地球上。任何車隊或部隊
Our unification of thoughts is more powerful
a weapon than any fleet or army on earth.
我們是一家人......
We are one people...
難道我們用光頭黨作為群眾演員？
Did we use skinheads as extras?
- 一對夫婦的人都告訴我的。
- 是啊。
- A couple of people have told me that.
- Yeah.
我們付光頭黨？ 我已經
得到了我的工資單光頭？
We paid skinheads? I've
got skinheads on my payroll?
- 他們有你想要看看。
- 光頭黨？
- They had a look you wanted.
- The skinheads?
- 是啊。
- 好吧，讓我們記住這對我們自己。
- Yeah.
- Okay, let's keep that to ourselves.
我們為準。
We shall prevail.
1月24日，蘋果電腦
將推出的Macintosh電腦。
On January 24th, Apple Computer
will introduce Macintosh.
- 還有誰知道？
- Who else knows?
- Who else knows what?
- 那我們付出的恐怖分子是在我們的電視廣告。
- 約翰·...
- That we paid terrorists to be in our TV commercial.
- John...
他們是錯的廣告，但
他們是一個很好的電路板。 優秀的人才。
They were wrong about the ad, but
they're a good board. Good people.
他們唯一的問題......他們的
的問題是，它們是人。
Their only problem... Their
problem is that they're people.
人。 人的本質
東西要克服。
People. The very nature of people
is something to be overcome.
當我運行百事可樂，我們有很多
成功專注於18至55歲的孩子
When I was running Pepsi, we had a lot
of success focusing on 18-to-55-year-olds
- 誰沒有暴力仇恨團體的成員。
- 我知道了。
- who weren't members of violent hate groups.
- I get it.
你不被敵人包圍。
You're not surrounded by enemies.
我們快到了。
We're almost there.
我來回的迪倫。
I'm back and forth on the Dylan.
我可以舉一個不同的詩句。
I might quote a different verse.
有什麼選擇呢？
What are the choices?
「對於失敗者現在稍後會取勝，」
"For the loser now will be later to win,"
- 這是我們所擁有的。
- 嗯 - 嗯。 要麼？
- which is what we have.
- Mm-hmm. Or?
「來吧母親和父親
全國各地「
"Come mothers and fathers
throughout the land"
也不要罵什麼
你無法理解。
and don't criticize what
you can't understand.
你的兒女「......
Your sons and your daughters"...
「超出你的命令。」
"Are beyond your command."
我剛剛失去了一百
雄鹿以安迪·赫茲菲爾德。
I just lost a hundred
bucks to Andy Hertzfeld.
他說，你把它改為了詩句。
He said you'd change it to that verse.
我們得到了45秒。 我想
用它來問你一個問題。
We got 45 seconds. I want to
use it to ask you a question.
為什麼採用誰的人覺得像
他們被拒絕，而不是選擇？
Why do people who are adopted feel like
they were rejected instead of selected?
這不知從哪裏冒出。
That came out of nowhere.
「你的兒女
超出你的命令。
"Your sons and your daughters
are beyond your command.
您的老路迅速老齡化「。
Your old road is rapidly aging."
所以，去他媽的自己，因為
我的名字是史蒂夫·喬布斯，
So go fuck yourself, because
my name is Steve Jobs,
和時代，他們是 - 起了變化「。
and the times, they are a-changin'.
我不覺得被拒絕。
I don't feel rejected.
- 你確定？
- 非常確定。
- You're sure?
- Very sure.
「因為它是不喜歡寶寶
出生，父母看，並說，
'Cause it's not like the baby is
born and the parents look and say,
「不，我們沒有興趣在這一個。」
"Nah, we're not interested in this one."
在另一方面，有人卻選擇你。
On the other hand, someone did choose you.
它不具有控制權。
It's having no control.
你發現你不在循環
You find out you were out of the loop
當最關鍵的事件
在你的生命在運動中進行了設置。
when the most crucial events
in your life were set in motion.
只要你有控制權。
As long as you have control.
我不明白的人誰放棄。
I don't understand people who give it up.
是什麼促使赫茨菲爾德作出這樣的選擇？
What inspired Hertzfeld to make that bet?
他警告我，是你的
父親的身影可能是危險的。
He was warning me that being your
father figure could be dangerous.
保持你的100塊錢。 我
堅持與第一首詩歌。
Keep your 100 bucks. I'm
sticking with the first verse.
好。
Good.
- 什麼是地獄意思？
- 什麼也沒有。
- What the hell does he mean?
- Nothing.
我以你為榮。
I'm proud of you.
謝謝老大。
Thank you, boss.
這是我高興地介紹
我的朋友和蘋果公司的CEO，
It's my pleasure to introduce
my friend and the CEO of Apple,
約翰斯卡利。
John Sculley.
約翰？
John?
是嗎？
Yeah?
麗莎做了Mac上的一幅畫。
Lisa made a painting on the Mac.
的Macintosh電腦，蘋果的近
神話的家用電腦，
The Macintosh, Apple's near
mythological home computer,
已經有了一個艱難的開端在
它的戰鬥與行業巨頭IBM。
has gotten off to a rocky start in
its battle with industry titan IBM.
替換原來的銷售預計將
一百萬在第一季度，​​
With sales originally projected to
be a million in the first quarter,
蘋果僅售出35000
人性化的機器
Apple has sold only 35,000
of the user-friendly machines
的幾個月中，因為它的
已提供給客戶。
in the months since it's
been available to customers.
作者史蒂夫·喬布斯的堅持
The insistence by Steve Jobs
，它有什麼
叫端至端控制，的
that it have what's
called end-to-end control,
這是說這是不兼容的方式
與最外側的硬體或軟體，的
which is a way of saying that it's not compatible
with most outside hardware or software,
是在莎士比亞的缺陷
機器有的潛力。
is the Shakespearean flaw in a
machine that had potential.
蘋果電腦關閉
今天它的兩個工廠
Apple Computers closed
two of its factories today
在令人失望的銷售之後。
in the wake of disappointing sales.
你知道有多少蘋果電腦
上個月共售出？ 500。
Do you know how many Macs
were sold last month? 500.
在有些驚訝的舉動
但並不是所有的華爾街，
In a move that surprised some
but not all on Wall Street,
的董事會
蘋果電腦今天投票
the board of directors of
Apple Computers voted today
解雇其聯合創始人史蒂夫·喬布斯。
to fire its cofounder Steve Jobs.
難道他跳還是他推？
Did he jump or was he pushed?
他的前上司，蘋果CEO約翰·
斯卡利，拒絕發表評論。
His ex-boss, Apple CEO John
Sculley, refused to comment.
不過，在接受記者專訪時，
However, in an exclusive interview,
史蒂夫·沃茲尼亞克已經關上了
他的老朋友史蒂夫·喬布斯的完整性。
Steve Wozniak has slammed the
integrity of his old friend Steve Jobs.
他叫喬布斯的
侮辱和傷害的人。
He calls Jobs an
insulting and hurtful guy.
工作是打回用
新的公司和新的計算機。
Jobs is hitting back with a
new company and a new computer.
蘋果有新的競爭者。
Apple has a new competitor.
史蒂夫·喬布斯的黑色立方體為
針對教育市場。
Steve Jobs's black cube is
aimed at the education market.
很少有人有能力
讓世界等待，
Few people have the ability
to make the world wait,
但這正是喬布斯
與他的新公司在做，下一步
but that is just what Jobs is
doing with his new company, NeXT.
焦點似乎有點尖銳。
Focus seems kind of sharp.
在幻燈片上？
On the slide?
地上。 銷點。
The floor. The pin spot.
我認為，我們希望有一個大家關注的焦點。
I think we want a sharp focus.
不要往心裏去。 只是
馬戲團的審美不是一個球迷。
Don't take it personally. Just
not a fan of the circus aesthetic.
好吧，讓我們在這裏舉行。 我們要
要上去和調整的工具。
All right, let's hold here. We're gonna
have to go up and refocus the instruments.
只一個。 30是好的。
Just one. The 30 is fine.
雖然我們控股，有
好心人在貴賓室。
While we're holding, there are
well-wishers in the VIP room.
而沃茲就在這裏。
And Woz is here.
史蒂夫·沃茲尼亞克。 是。 非常感謝。
Steve Wozniak. Yes. Thank you very much.
和安迪·赫茲菲爾德。
And Andy Hertzfeld.
安迪·赫茲菲爾德。 謝謝。
Andy Hertzfeld. Thank you.
約翰斯卡利也在這裏。
John Sculley is here too.
這是很好的，他在這裏。
It's nice that he's here.
真？ 我不認為
這是非常不錯的。
Really? I don't think
it's very nice at all.
你必須看到他們。 他們
想瞻仰。
You have to see them. They
wanna pay their respects.
如果他們尊重，我們最好
一切還是在蘋果公司現在。
If they were respectful, we'd
all still be at Apple right now.
看...
Look...
如果他們真的希望我好，
他們會堅持自己。
If they really wished me well,
they'd keep to themselves.
- 我能告訴你一些事嗎？
- 我不認為他們確實希望我好。
- Can I tell you something?
- I don't think they do wish me well.
但我全部用權
那。 我在蘋果公司。
But I'm all right with
that. I'm over Apple.
我在Mac和沃茲和斯卡利，
I got over the Mac and Woz and Sculley,
你得到了相同的方法
你高中時的戀人。
the same way you get over
your high school sweetheart.
建一個新的。
Build a new one.
- 我能告訴你一些事嗎？
- 是。
- Can I tell you something?
- Yes.
你說你不會與他們競爭，
You said you wouldn't compete with them,
但你設計了一個計算機
專門針對教育市場，
but you designed a computer
specifically for the education market,
他們假定的自己。
which they putatively own.
所以，我認為這很酷，他們在這裏。
So, I think it's cool they're here.
他們起訴我。
They're suing me.
仍然。
Still.
這是很好的，他們來了。
It was nice they came.
他們不是坦蕩。
They're not being magnanimous.
他們希望它看起來
像一個友好的離婚。
They want it to look
like an amicable divorce.
歷史不會記得喬
迪馬吉奧好心傾倒瑪麗蓮。
History doesn't remember Joe
DiMaggio kindly for dumping Marilyn.
史蒂夫？
Steve?
你怎麼了？
What's your problem?
我不知道，但我敢肯定
這可以追溯到給你。
I don't know, but I'm sure
it can be traced back to you.
你知道，我是一個誰
必須解釋你的人。
You know, I'm the one who
has to explain you to people.
$ 100,000保蘭德的企業標誌
$100,000 to Paul Rand for a corporate logo
當我們甚至不知道
正是我們公司生產的。
when we didn't even know
what our company made.
A $ 65萬的模具多維數據集，
A $650,000 mold for the cube,
因為上帝禁止
角度是90.1，而不是90。
because God forbid the
angles be 90.1 instead of 90.
我不准的角度
是90.1，而不是90。
I forbid the angles to
be 90.1 instead of 90.
這盒可能是上
顯示在古根海姆。
That box could be on
display at the Guggenheim.
不要給他們的理由說給新聞界
Don't give them reason to say to the press
你有你的肩膀上的芯片。
you have a chip on your shoulder.
你會為我做？
Will you do that for me?
我沒有在我的肩膀上的芯片。
I don't have a chip on my shoulder.
好吧好吧。
Okay, okay.
但不給他們一個理由說你做。
But don't give them a reason to say you do.
我不。
I don't.
- 這是正確的態度。
- 這不是一種態度。
- That's the right attitude.
- That's not an attitude.
他們會打電話給我回
一分鐘看光。
They're gonna call me back in
a minute to look at the light.
- 獲取一個出路。
- 精細！
- Get one out of the way.
- Fine!
- 是啊？
- 是啊。
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- 還有一件事。
- 當然。
- One more thing.
- Sure.
沒有問題的新聞後。
No questions from the press after.
沒有為什麼？
No... Why?
直到我有更好的
答案，沒有新聞無濟於事。
Until I have better
answers, no press avail.
有人問我在哪裏，你只要
看見我，我馬上就回來。
Somebody asks where I am, you just
saw me, and I'll be right back.
好。
Okay.
誰你想先？
Who do you want first?
給我史蒂夫·沃茲尼亞克的臉。
Bring me the face of Steve Wozniak.
不掛斷。
Hang on.
- 我還以為你去上學。
- 不掛斷。
- I thought you went to school.
- Hang on.
你們應該去上學
一小時前。 我還以為你離開。
You were supposed to go to school
an hour ago. I thought you left.
我沒有叫醒我的媽媽
在今天凌晨。
I didn't wake up my mom
on time this morning.
之前也它發生了。
It's happened before too.
我醒來報警，然後
我穿好衣服，吃早餐，
I wake up with the alarm and then
I get dressed and eat breakfast,
但有時我忘了看
這是什麼時候在那之後。
but sometimes I forget to see
what time it is after that.
- 為什麼沒有你媽媽剛剛成立了自己的鬧鐘？
- 這是我的家務事之一。
- Why doesn't your mom just set her own alarm clock?
- It's one of my chores.
我不明白，有
做，為什麼你還是...
I don't understand what that has
to do with why you're still...
哪裏是你的母親呢？
Where's your mother?
她去找到一個公用電話。
She went to find a pay phone.
一個小時前，她說...
An hour ago, she said...
你沒有舉手。
You don't have to raise your hand.
- 你說，這是關閉的一點點。
- 它是。
- You said it was off by a little.
- It is.
- 我只是衡量它。
- 喬安娜...
- I just measured it.
- Joanna...
四面整整一英尺。
Exactly a foot on all four sides.
有六個側面。
There are six sides.
但你不應該
在這裏現在。
But you're not supposed
to be here right now.
我們知道，如果四個邊
是彼此相等，
We know if four of the sides
are equal to each other,
其他兩個必須相等。
the other two must be equal as well.
在上，下，左，右
The top, bottom, right and left
大約一毫米短
比的正面和背面。
are about a millimeter shorter
than the front and back.
他們不是。 我衡量他們。
They're not. I measured them.
麗莎，我是那種在設計方面的專家。
Lisa, I'm kind of an expert in design.
這是一個20美分的統治者。 您認為
有一個機會，它可能會關閉？
And that's a 20-cent ruler. You think
there's a chance it could be off?
如果我有另外的尺子，我會衡量
這把尺子，但我真的懷疑它的關閉。
If I had another ruler, I would measure
this ruler, but I really doubt it's off.
- 當你的媽媽回來，你必須去上學。
- 因為它是一個統治者！
- When your mother comes back, you have to go to school.
- Because it's a ruler!
為什麼關閉？
Why is it off?
- 你聽到我剛才說的嗎？
- 是。
- Did you hear what I just said?
- Yes.
因為有時它似乎像
你剛才一直說你想要什麼
Because sometimes it seems like
you just keep saying what you want
不聽。
without listening.
我在聽。
I'm listening.
- 是否有您所需要的？
- 沒有。
- Is there something you need?
- No.
為什麼不是一個完美的立方體？
Why isn't it a perfect cube?
- 你以前問過我。
- 我忘了是什麼了。
- You've asked me before.
- I forget what it is.
這是一個光學異常。
It's an optical anomaly.
對人眼來說，一個完美的
立方體看起來並不像一個魔方，
To the human eye, a perfect
cube doesn't look like a cube,
所以我們把它大約一毫米
比在兩側腳短。
so we made it roughly a millimeter
shorter than a foot on two sides.
什麼是異常？
What's an anomaly?
你問我之前太。
You've asked me that before too.
我不知道為什麼你繼續這樣做。
I don't know why you keep doing that.
這是一個例外。 某物
不適合的模式。
It's an exception. Something
that doesn't fit a pattern.
你必須去上學。 進來！
You have to go to school. Come in!
我覺得你們兩個已經滿足。
I think you two have met.
你好，老朋友。
Hello, old friend.
- 你看起來很好。
- 你也是。 你也是。
- You look well.
- So do you. So do you.
他們告訴我喬治
準備好你看看焦點。
And they're telling me George is
ready for you to look at the focus.
就拿跟我走。
Take a walk with me.
- 這是麗莎？
- 是啊。
- Is this Lisa?
- Yeah.
- 這不可能是麗莎。
- 它是。
- This can't be Lisa.
- It is.
- 麗莎的這個大。
- 他們得到更高。 加油。
- Lisa's this big.
- They get taller. Come on.
- 你記得我嗎？
- 她不。
- Do you remember me?
- She doesn't.
我是你爸爸的朋友史蒂夫·沃茲尼亞克。
I'm your dad's friend Steve Wozniak.
對不起。 我不記得你。
I apologize. I don't remember you.
你很有禮貌。
You're very polite.
- 沃茲？
- 是啊。
- Woz?
- Yeah.
Chrisann是在現收現付
電話。 你會找到她？
Chrisann's at a pay
phone. Would you find her?
是啊。
Yeah.
好熱鬧。
Good turnout.
- 偉大的投票率。
- 是啊。
- Great turnout.
- Yeah.
- 「瘋狂太棒了。」
- 瘋狂大。
- "Insanely great."
- Insanely great.
這是我們第一次
沒玩過的同一支球隊。
This is the first time we
haven't played for the same team.
這就像你正在釋放
你的第一張個人專輯。
It's like you're releasing
your first solo album.
我，呃...我很欣賞你
邀請我到發射。
I, uh... I appreciate your
inviting me to the launch.
我只是想徹底清除。
I just want to wipe the slate clean.
這正是我想要的。
這就是為什麼我來到後台。
That's exactly what I want.
That's why I came backstage.
我想讓你知道，嗯，
我會在那裏和你在一起。
I want you to know, um,
I'll be out there with you.
任何機會，我可以讓你
代替我去了那裏？
Any chance I can get you to
go out there instead of me?
我愛你，史蒂夫。
I love you, Steve.
我也愛你，沃茲。
I love you too, Woz.
你知道，說了一些事情。
You know, some things were said.
他們是。 他們在公眾中說。
They were. They were said in public.
他們出版。 被
你被迫做呢？
They were published. Were
you pressured to do it?
當時我是什麼？
Was I what?
一探究竟。 這是樂團
坑舊金山歌劇院。
Check it out. It's the orchestra
pit for the San Francisco Opera.
當時我被迫做呢？
Was I pressured to do it?
我曾經遇到小澤征爾在坦格烏德。
I once met Seiji Ozawa at Tanglewood.
雷鳴般的指揮。
A thunderous conductor.
不敬虔的藝術性和細微之處。
Ungodly artfulness and nuance.
我問他到底什麼一個
導體做一個節拍器不能。
And I asked him what exactly a
conductor does that a metronome can't.
- 令人驚訝的，他......
- 他沒有打活狗屎嗎？
- Surprisingly, he...
- He didn't beat the living shit out of you?
那就對了。 不，他說，「
音樂家們演奏著樂器。「
That's right. No, he said, "The
musicians play their instruments."
我玩樂團。「
I play the orchestra."
這感覺就像一些聽起來
不錯，但並不意味著什麼。
That feels like something that sounds
good, but doesn't mean anything.
馬庫拉，斯卡利......難道他們問
你去渣我關在報刊上？
Markkula, Sculley... Did they ask
you to slag me off in the press?
我有理由生氣。
I had reason to be angry.
- 難道不是嗎？
- 絕對不。
- Did they?
- Absolutely not.
但是，他們問你談談。
But they asked you to talk.
蘋果被圍困。
你剛剛離開了公司。
Apple was under siege.
You'd just left the company.
必須有人交談的記者。
Someone had to talk to the press.
我就在這裏，沃茲。 公司留給我。
I'm right here, Woz. The company left me.
我懇求你。 我懇求你。
I begged you. I begged you.
蘋果II占
為收入的70％。
The Apple II accounted
for 70% of the revenue.
你認為什麼是要發生的事？
What did you think was gonna happen?
你根本不夠關心
蘋果II或麗莎。
You didn't care enough about
the Apple II or the Lisa.
讓我們真正清楚。
Let's be really clear.
我不關心的所有關於
蘋果II或麗莎。
I didn't care at all about
the Apple II or the Lisa.
我不是被迫這樣做。
I wasn't pressured to do it.
我向新聞界說的是一個誠實的，
如果磨礪，是我認為反映。
What I said to the press was an honest,
if tempered, reflection of what I believed.
- 沃茲。
- 是啊？
- Woz.
- Yeah?
什麼他媽的是你的手腕？
What the fuck is on your wrist?
- 你想知道嗎？
- 我簡直等不及了。
- You wanna know?
- I literally can't wait.
每個人的會是
10年來穿這些。
Everyone's gonna be
wearing these in 10 years.
這是一個尿血的手錶，用做數碼管。
It's a Nixie watch, made using Nixie tubes.
這實際上是
40歲的技術。
This is actually
40-year-old technology.
冷陰極管。 他們是
工作在140伏。
Cold cathode tubes. They're
operating at 140 volts.
我傾斜我的手腕45
度，它就在那裏。
I tilt my wrist 45
degrees, it's right there.
時，分，秒。
Hours, minutes and seconds.
我們的思想工作的方式。 看那個。
The way our minds work. Look at that.
幫我一個忙。 將手錶
未來就像你在飛機上
Do me a favor. Set the watch
ahead like you're on a plane
而只是改變時區。
and just changed time zones.
不是一個問題。
Not a problem.
擰開了。 只要按下按鈕。
Unscrew that. Just hit the button.
打擾一下。 空姐？ 該男子下一個
對我來說似乎是引爆了​​炸彈。
Excuse me. Flight attendant? The man next
to me would appear to be detonating a bomb.
你覺得這看起來像一個炸彈。
You think this looks like a bomb.
即使是現在，我不是100％肯定它不是。
Even right now, I'm not 100% sure it isn't.
- 我想，也許一旦人們習慣了它...
- 沒有。
- I think maybe once people get used to it...
- No.
我生氣了。
I was angry.
你剛才說有關Apple II的事情，
和你的方式進行治療團隊...
You were saying things about the Apple II,
and the way you were treating the team...
沃茲。 你得到的免費券生活。
Woz. You get a free pass for life.
我得回去舞台。 我們有
兩分鐘排練時間離開了。
I got to get back onstage. We got
two minutes of rehearsal time left.
你瞭解居高臨下
剛才是？ 也許你不知道。
Do you understand how condescending
that just was? Maybe you don't.
我不希望看到你得到拖累
關閉塑料手銬飛機。
I don't want to see you get dragged
off an airplane in plastic handcuffs.
我得到一個免費通行證，從您的生活嗎？
I get a free pass for life from you?
你給了通...
Y-Y-您給我吧？
You give out the pass...
Y-Y-You give them to me?
你要去有中風，小傢伙。
You're gonna have a stroke, little buddy.
你做了什麼？ 你做了什麼？
What did you do? What did you do?
為什麼麗莎沒有聽說過我？
Why has Lisa not heard of me?
媽的，男人，多少
四年級學生聽說過嗎？
Shit, man, how many
fourth-graders have heard of you?
你可以不寫代碼。 你不是
一個工程師。 你不是一個設計師。
You can't write code. You're not
an engineer. You're not a designer.
你不能把錘子釘子。
You can't put a hammer to a nail.
我建了電路板。
I built the circuit board.
圖形界面
從Xerox PARC的被偷了。
The graphical interface
was stolen from Xerox PARC.
傑夫·拉斯金是在Mac團隊的領導者
你扔在他面前脫下自己的項目。
Jef Raskin was the leader of the Mac team
before you threw him off his own project.
一切......有人
其他設計中。
Everything... Someone
else designed the box.
那麼怎麼來的10次在一天，
So how come 10 times in a day,
我讀「史蒂夫·喬布斯是個天才」？
I read "Steve Jobs is a genius"?
你是做什麼？
What do you do?
我玩樂團。
I play the orchestra.
而你是一個優秀的音樂家。
你坐在那裏。
And you're a good musician.
You sit right there.
你最好在你行的。
You're the best in your row.
我來這裏是為了清除空氣中。
I came here to clear the air.
- 你知道我為什麼來這裏？
- 你剛才不是回答這個問題？
- Do you know why I came here?
- Didn't you just answer that?
我來到這裏是因為
你會被殺。
I came here because
you're gonna get killed.
您的計算機會失敗。
Your computer's gonna fail.
你有一個大學，
大學顧問委員會
You had a college and
university advisory board
告訴你他們需要一個功能強大
工作站2000到3000。
telling you they need a powerful
workstation for 2,000 to 3,000.
你在6500價位的下一步。
You've priced NeXT at 6,500.
並且不包括
可選的$ 3000名硬盤，
And that doesn't include the
optional $3,000 hard drive,
人們會發現是不可選的。
which people will discover isn't optional.
因為光盤
是太弱，無法做任何事情。
Because the optical disk
is too weak to do anything.
而$ 2,500激光打印機
共計為$ 12,000元。
And the $2,500 laser printer
brings the total to $12,000.
而且在整個世界，
你是唯一的人
And in the entire world,
you are the only person
誰在乎它的
住在一個完美的立方體。
who cares that it's
housed in a perfect cube.
你會被殺死。
You're gonna get killed.
我來到這裏站在
你旁邊，而出現這種情況
And I came here to stand
next to you while that happens
因為這就是朋友們。
because that's what friends do.
這就是男人。 我不需要你的密碼。
That's what men do. I don't need your pass.
我們回去，所以不說話
對我來說，我是其他人。
We go back, so don't talk
to me like I'm other people.
我就是知道只有一個
I'm the only one that knows
這傢伙在這裏是一個你發明的。
that this guy here is someone you invented.
我站在你，因為那
完美的立方體，什麼也不做
I'm standing by you because that
perfect cube that does nothing
即將成為最大的單一故障
is about to be the single biggest failure
在個人計算機的歷史。
in the history of personal computing.
告訴我什麼我不知道。
Tell me something else I don't know.
- 回到舞台上？
- 我們沒時間了。
- Back onstage?
- We're out of time.
他們得拖
舞台，然後打開房子。
They've got to mop the
stage and open the house.
如果它崩潰，崩潰，對不對？
If it crashes, it crashes, right?
你會是個笑話。
You'll make a joke.
我會成為一個笑話。
I'll make a joke.
如果它崩潰，崩潰。
If it crashes, it crashes.
這是一個很好的口號。 「下一個。
如果它崩潰，崩潰「。
It's a good slogan. "NeXT.
If it crashes, it crashes."
我不只是在談論演示，史蒂夫。
I'm not just talking about the demo, Steve.
如果坦克，我們不吞下氰化物。
If it tanks, we don't swallow cyanide.
- 我們回到繪圖板。
- 沒有更多的繪圖板。
- We go back to the drawing board.
- No more drawing boards.
發明了埃茲爾兩次，你
沒有得到任何更多的繪圖板。
Invent the Edsel twice, you
don't get any more drawing boards.
告訴我的計劃是什麼。
Tell me what the plan is.
你要告訴我
計劃，因為我不知道。
You have to tell me the
plan, because I don't know.
你走動像
你有「不能輸」的卡。
You're walking around like
you've got "Can't Lose" cards.
該計劃將揭示自己
當你準備好你看到它。
The plan will reveal itself to
you when you're ready to see it.
請問我要降酸？
Will I have to drop acid?
不能傷害。
Couldn't hurt.
是否有計劃？
Is there a plan?
難道我讓你失望？
Have I ever let you down?
每一個該死的時間。
Every single goddamn time.
- 然後我所致。
- 在那兒？
- Then I'm due.
- Is there?
喬安娜，有一個計劃。
Joanna, there's a plan.
我只是不想讓你在
在那裏你說謊的人的位置。
I just don't wanna put you in a
position where you're lying to people.
開始遲到15分鐘，以便Avie將能
重新編譯，給我們一個戰鬥的機會。
Start 15 minutes late so Avie can
recompile and give us a fighting chance.
耶穌基督。 多少次
我們要怎麼有這樣的騙子？
Jesus Christ. How many times
are we gonna have this con...
- 我們沒有起步較晚，永遠！
- 精細！
- We're not starting late, ever!
- Fine!
- 我們不是永遠起步較晚。
- 晚了。
- We're not ever starting late.
- Late.
但是，在你來
倒在起步晚？
But where do you come
down on starting late?
麗莎一直在做這件事情，她
問我的東西，我已經告訴她了。
Lisa's been doing this thing where she
asks me about stuff I've already told her.
她問我問題，我知道
她已經知道答案。
She asks me questions, and I know
she already knows the answers.
那是什麼呢？
What's that about?
孩子們做到這一點時，他們嚇壞了1
他們的父母是心情不好。
Kids do that when they're scared one
of their parents is in a bad mood.
他們試圖讓你說話
對自己喜歡的東西。
They try to get you talking
about something you like.
這是很常見的，並且可以通過被處理
跟她的事，她喜歡。
It's very common and can be treated by
talking to her about things she likes.
你有什麼經驗
或培訓在這個領域？
Do you have any experience
or training in this field?
沒有。
No.
告訴他們打開房子。
Tell them to open the house.
- 是麗莎在哪裏？
- 她的身邊。
- Where's Lisa?
- She's around.
- 這意味著什麼？
- 她周圍的建築物運行。
- What does that mean?
- She's running around the building.
一個小時前，你說你
被帶她上學。
An hour ago, you said you
were taking her to school.
她求我讓她留下來。 那裏
是誰的父親會這麼愛...
She begged me to let her stay. There
are fathers who would so love...
這是錯誤的，好嗎？ 這在道德上是
錯了，這是錯誤的腸胃。
It is wrong, okay? It is morally
wrong, it's parentally wrong.
這是錯誤的，你用麗莎
從我財路的方式。
It is wrong for you to use Lisa
as a way of getting money from me.
她知道，如果她不已經，
這是她的主要用途。
She will know, if she doesn't already,
that that is your primary use for her.
她會恨你
你的餘生。
She will hate you for
the rest of your life.
她會看，如果她已經不，那
她的母親是一個女人誰站起來的人。
She will see, if she doesn't already, that
her mother is a woman who stands up to men.
活過他們。
By living off of them.
由於沒有讓自己變得
監禁，他們降級。
By not letting myself be
imprisoned and degraded by them.
囚禁？ 我不能擺脫你。
Imprisoned? I can't get rid of you.
我需要一個醫生，我需要一個牙醫。
I need a doctor and I need a dentist.
我從大學輟學後，
學期，不過，沒關係，讓我們一起來看看。
I dropped out of college after a
semester, but, okay, let's have a look.
你會支持你
女兒和她的母親。
You will support your
daughter and her mother.
你有沒有僱人
$ 1,500到保佑你的房子？
Did you pay someone
$1,500 to bless your house?
- 你聽到我說的嗎？
- 你是否？
- Did you hear what I said?
- Did you?
我不記得有多少了，史蒂夫。
I don't remember how much it was, Steve.
- 這是$ 1500元。
- 那麼，他們不這樣做免費的。
- It was $1,500.
- Well, they don't do it for free.
他們不知道。 他們收取$ 1500元。
They don't. They charge $1,500.
我如何度過......他媽的。 您
知道了，我甚至會...
How I spend... Fuck. You
know, I'm not even gonna...
是你約說，「我怎麼花
我的錢是你管得著嗎「的？
Were you about to say, "How I spend
my money is none of your business"?
我有一個鼻竇感染，
我要去看牙醫了。
I have a sinus infection and
I need to see a dentist too.
所以，你可以看到你的祝福
預算本來可以更好地用。
So you can see how your blessing
budget could have been better spent.
喜歡上一個完美的立方體？
Like on a perfect cube?
- 看看我，Chrisann。
- 什麼？
- Look at me, Chrisann.
- What?
- 你知道我是誰了吧？
- 是。
- You know who I am, right?
- Yes.
- 你知道我認識的人。
- 你在說什麼？
- And you know I know people.
- What are you talking about?
看著我。 你知道的
我認識的人，他們知道的人。
Look at me. And you know the
people I know, they know people.
這是什麼？
What is this?
如果我以後再，你已經聽到
泛起了一碗麥片在麗莎的頭...
If I ever hear again that you've
thrown a cereal bowl at Lisa's head...
- 什麼？
- 我的專用線的要響，
- What?
- My private line's gonna ring,
而在另一端的聲音
是會說，「我們所有的設置。」
and a voice on the other end
is gonna say, "We're all set."
- 這就是我要學習，你就死定了。
- 你CRA ...
- That's how I'll learn that you're dead.
- Are you cra...
我扔在地上的碗。
I threw the bowl on the floor.
我沒有在她的頭上扔。
I didn't throw it at her head.
她甚至沒有在房間裏。
She wasn't even in the room.
她無處...我扔
碗在地板上。
She was nowhere... I threw
the bowl on the floor.
她是一個小女孩。 你嚇著她。
She's a little girl. You're scaring her.
我是一個成年男子。 你嚇到我了。
I'm a grown man. You're scaring me.
清除垃圾是件苦差事。
Taking out the garbage is a chore.
收拾桌子是件苦差事。
Clearing the table is a chore.
喚醒你早上起來
只是他媽的讓人毛骨悚然。
Waking you up in the morning
is just fucking creepy.
- 請告訴我更多關於為人父母。
- 我們都在這裏完成。
- Please teach me more about being a parent.
- We're all done here.
這意味著很多來自何處
人誰也不會承認自己就是其中之一。
It means so much coming from
someone who won't admit he is one.
- 停止尖叫麗莎。
- 我給她的責任。
- Stop screaming at Lisa.
- I give her responsibilities.
- 得到它了。
- 有一天，她會感謝我的。
- Got it.
- One day she's gonna thank me for it.
- 也許在你睡覺的。
- 滾開！
- Probably in your sleep.
- Fuck off!
好。
Okay.
我從來沒有...我從來不扔
什麼在她的頭上。
I never... I never threw
anything at her head.
史蒂夫。
Steve.
我永遠不會。
I never would.
事情不是變得如此，因為你這麼說。
Things don't become so because you say so.
未來將有更多的錢在你的
帳戶由業務結束。
There'll be more money in your
account by the end of business.
- 是你是漂亮的？
- 哦耶。
- Were you being nice?
- Oh, yeah.
- 安迪的旁邊。
- 赫茨菲爾德或坎寧安？
- Andy's next.
- Hertzfeld or Cunningham?
赫茨菲爾德。 他玩Avie將
Tevanian在計算機後台上。
Hertzfeld. He's playing with Avie
Tevanian on the computer backstage.
女士們先生們，
房子現在是開放的。
Ladies and gentlemen,
the house is now open.
- 玩在數千人面前。
- 史蒂夫！
- Playing in front of thousands of people.
- Steve!
他後來能做到這一點，喬爾？
我們走在8分鐘。
Can he do it later, Joel?
We go in eight minutes.
- 我可以得到一個快速的反應，記者今天上午？
- 怎麼了？
- Can I get a quick reaction to the press this morning?
- What about it?
- 它的大小，體積。
- 我會告訴你的背景？
- The size of it, the volume.
- I'll tell you on background...
- 我希望從史蒂夫報價。
- 我會告訴你的背景
- I was hoping for a quote from Steve.
- I'll tell you on background
我從未見過任何東西
喜歡它的高科技產業。
that I've never seen anything
like it in the tech industry.
我叫​​華爾街日報
拿出一個整版廣告的今天，
I called the Wall Street Journal
to take out a full-page ad for today,
而你知道他們的銷售員說的嗎？
and do you know what their sales guy said?
「何必呢？它會像通知
梅西明天是聖誕節。「
"Why bother? It'd be like notifying
Macy's that tomorrow is Christmas."
- 你看到了斯圖爾特·艾爾索普通訊？
- 我做到了。
- You saw the Stewart Alsop newsletter?
- I did.
對不起，喬安娜，我需要
讓史蒂夫的紀錄。
I'm sorry, Joanna, I need
to get Steve on the record.
該標題是「親愛的NeXT公司，
我什麼時候能拿到我的機器？「
The headline was "Dear NeXT,
when can I get my machine?"
- 當是嗎？
- 我們將宣佈出貨日期在未來8到10周。
- When can he?
- We'll announce the ship date in the next eight to 10 weeks.
艾爾索普不是談論的發貨日期。
Alsop's not talking about the ship date.
他想知道他什麼時候
可以得到一個一起玩。
He wants to know when he
can get one to play with.
我們有很多尊重斯圖爾特·艾爾索普，
We have a lot of respect for Stewart Alsop,
我們希望得到一台機器到他的手
這樣他就可以告訴他的訂戶了。
and we want to get a machine into his hands
so he can tell his subscribers about it.
- 而當將有多大呢？
- 很快。
- And when will that be?
- Very soon.
幾天？ 一周？
Couple of days? A week?
關閉記錄。
Off the record.
- 關閉記錄？
- 完全。
- Off the record?
- Completely.
- 我們認為...
- 他會得到它時，它的完成。
- We think...
- He'll get it when it's finished.
這還不算完？
It's not finished?
它幾乎已經完成。
It's almost finished.
- 我一直在看你排練演示了三個星期。
- 是啊。
- I've been watching you rehearse the demo for three weeks.
- Yeah.
- 還剩下什麼？
- 一個小東西。
- What's left?
- A little thing.
- 什麼？
- 我認為這是不夠的。
- What?
- I think that's enough.
我們關閉記錄，和喬爾總是
一直善於理解細微之處。
We're off the record, and Joel's always
been good at understanding nuance.
什麼是留下來完成？
What's left to finish?
我想，在通俗地說，你會
不得不說，我們沒有一個操作系統。
I guess, in layman's terms, you'd
have to say we don't have an OS.
- 一個操作系統？
- 是啊。
- An operating system?
- Yeah.
- 什麼意思？
- 嗯，操作系統是運行在計算機上。
- What do you mean?
- Well, the OS is what runs the computer.
事實上，它的排序是計算機。
In fact, it sort of is the computer.
它是如何一直運行？ 怎麼樣
它會運行今天早上？
How has it been running? How's
it gonna run this morning?
你是什​​麼意思，你沒有一個操作系統？
What do you mean, you don't have an OS?
是這樣的。 阿瓦德斯·特凡尼安
是我們的首席軟體設計師，
It's like this. Avie Tevanian
is our chief software designer,
他寫了一個演示程序。
and he wrote a demo program.
這就像我們建立了一個偉大的汽車，
但我們還沒有建立發動機。
It's like we built a great car,
but we haven't built the engine.
所以我們把高爾夫球車電池
在那裏，使他走了一會兒。
So we put a golf cart battery
in there to make it go for a bit.
所有這些計算機知道該怎麼辦
現在的問題是證明自己。
All this computer knows how to do
right now is demonstrate itself.
你告訴我的唯一
你已經建立了一個黑色的魔方？
You're telling me the only thing
you've built is a black cube?
是。 是啊。
Yes. Yeah.
但是，是不是最酷
你見過黑色的魔方？
But isn't it the coolest
black cube you've ever seen?
這是...我們關閉記錄。
Is this... We're off the record.
這是一個策略或
問題？ 如果這是一個問題......
Is this a strategy or a
problem? If it's a problem...
不共享專有
知識與那個人。
Do not share proprietary
knowledge with that man.
這不是一個問題。
It's not a problem.
我想不明白也無妨。
I wouldn't understand it anyway.
我不明白，要麼，
我的名字是對的專利。
I don't understand it either,
and my name's on the patents.
- 它有電子郵件。
- 嗯，電子郵件的不只是技術專家了。
- It's got e-mail.
- Well, e-mail's not just for tech specialists anymore.
那麼，它是，但它不會。
Well, it is, but it won't be.
我認為電子郵件發送的下一台電腦上
只能由下一台電腦可以接收？
And I assume an e-mail sent on a NeXT computer
can only be received by a NeXT computer?
關閉，
端至端。
Closed,
end-to-end.
新的垃圾桶是錯誤的。
The new trash can is wrong.
我想告訴你我很欣賞
你把它付諸表決的時間，
I wanna tell you I appreciate
all the hours you put into it,
但我不能，因為它是多麼可怕的不是。
but I can't because of how terrible it is.
返回到另一個。
Go back to the other one.
為什麼我們仍然給
三個選項上的時鐘？
Why are we still giving
three options on the clock?
- 如何多的選擇，你想給？
- 二。 購買或沒有。
- How many options do you want to give?
- Two. Buy it or don't.
我能跟你說句話嗎？
Can I talk to you for a second?
ABSO-fruitly。
Abso-fruitly.
呃，你看，男人。 Avie將是被重新編譯，
Uh, look, man. Avie's been recompiling,
但他說，有可能是
一些小問題今天上午。
but he says there may be
some glitches this morning.
如果所有有一些小問題，
If all there are are some glitches,
這將是不可思議的幅度的勝利。
it'll be a triumph of miraculous magnitude.
你為什麼要翻譯的Avie將？
Why are you translating for Avie?
I-我不想讓他找出硬盤
這樣的故障在演示你的位置，
I-I didn't want him to find out the hard
way your position on glitches in a demo,
但它聽起來像是你已經成熟了。
but it sounds like you've mellowed.
我一直在成長，安迪。 我已經
在學習愛自己。
I've been growing, Andy. I've
been learning to love myself.
嗯。 我也不會永遠
夢見這是一個問題。
Hmm. I wouldn't have ever
dreamed that was a problem.
神奇的燒傷。
Fantastic burn.
你需要去你的座位。
You need to go to your seat.
如何麗莎，進入
一所學校有天賦的孩子？
How about Lisa, getting into
a school for gifted kids?
是啊，她進行了測試，
事實證明，她可以飛。
Yeah, she was tested and
it turns out she can fly.
- 嚴重的是，這是一個大問題。
- 我知道這是一個大問題。
- Seriously, it's a big deal.
- I know it's a big deal.
這就是為什麼我建了學校的建築物。
That's why I built the school a building.
- 嗯，我敢肯定，這不是為什麼她得到了。
- 真？
- Well, I'm sure that's not why she got in.
- Really?
嗯，我可以告訴你的東西
有趣的的Macworld？
Uh, can I show you something
funny from Macworld?
- 我想不出什麼我必須做的事情。
- 這會讓你感覺良好。
- I can't think of anything I have to do right now.
- It'll make you feel good.
- 喬安娜！ 看這個！
- 哦，安迪，他只得到了幾分鐘的時間。
- Joanna! Look at this!
- Oh, Andy, he's only got a couple of minutes.
它蓋川崎寫
Macworld大會。的你會喜歡這一點。
It's Guy Kawasaki writing in
Macworld. You're gonna like this.
好了，可大家都享受在後呢？
Well, can we all enjoy it later?
他寫了一個模仿新聞稿
蘋果收購了NeXT為您的操作系統。
He wrote a parody press release
about Apple buying NeXT for your OS.
他想像不久的將來，其中蘋果
需要你的操作系統和已買了NeXT，
He imagines a near future where Apple
needs your OS and has to buy NeXT,
並且，你回來擔任CEO。
and-and you come back as CEO.
他說，蓋茨，
He has Gates saying,
「有現在將是更多的創新
從喬布斯認為微軟可以複製「。
"There would now be more innovations
from Jobs that Microsoft could copy."
- 您可以稍後閱讀。
- 謝謝。
- You can read it later.
- Thanks.
她會一直沒有得到在
您捐贈的建築。
She would've gotten in without
you donating a building.
儘管如此，它的東西
在採訪中談到。
Still, it's something to
talk about in the interview.
好吧。 祝你好運。
All right. Good luck.
謝謝。
Thanks.
把那給我。 我會扔出來給你。
Give that to me. I'll throw it out for you.
我要掛到它。
I'm gonna hang on to it.
什麼？
What?
你準備好斯卡利？
You ready for Sculley?
打擾一下！
Excuse me!
麗莎！
Lisa!
你不能喊！
You can't shout!
麗莎？
Lisa?
你得走了。
You have to go.
它的危險在這裏。 這是
為什麼我讓其他人去做。
It's dangerous up here. That's
why I make other people do it.
你是誰的，我和你媽媽在隱瞞什麼？
Who are you hiding from, me or your mom?
我沒有隱瞞。
I'm not hiding.
我們走吧。
Let's go.
你是怎麼聽？
What were you listening to?
我聽兩個
同一首歌的版本。
I'm listening to two
versions of the same song.
然後，當我得到的兩端，我
快退，再次聽取他們的意見。
Then when I get to the ends, I
rewind to listen to them again.
這是同一首歌，但
版本不同。
It's the same song, but
the versions are different.
- 有什麼歌？
- 好。
- What's the song?
- Okay.
所以這是一個非常古老的歌曲，
這就是所謂的「雙方，現在。」
So it's a really old song, and
it's called "Both Sides, Now."
- 「雙方，現在」？
- 是啊。
- "Both Sides, Now"?
- Yeah.
這是什麼？
What's it about?
這是關於......有三種
詩：雲，愛情和生活。
It's about... There are three
verses: Clouds, love and life.
而人的歌聲唱
他們曾經認為的？
And the person singing is singing
that they used to think of...
他們曾經認為有關...
That they used to think about...
- 雲，愛情和生活？
- 對。
- Clouds, love and life?
- Right.
一種方式，是啊，但現在他們看起來
在他們的另一種方式，並且它們...
One way, yeah, but now they look
at them another way, and they...
他們已經得出的結論，他們
真不知道雲，愛情或人生。
They've come to the conclusion that they
really don't know clouds, love or life at all.
這些都是原話。
Those are the exact words.
是啊，Joni Mitchell的。
Yeah, Joni Mitchell.
「因為它不是一個真的老了
歌，除非我是一個真正的老傢伙。
'Cause it's not a really old
song, unless I'm a really old guy.
你必須去上學了。
You have to go to school now.
你要我告訴你
這兩個版本之間的差異？
Do you want me to tell you the
differences between the two versions?
現在。
Right now.
第一個版本是什麼樣的
你會打電話少女的事情。
The first version is the kind of
thing that you would call girlish.
我不是那個意思，我想知道
區別現在。
I didn't mean I want to know
the difference right now.
我的意思是，你必須去上學，現在。
I meant you have to go to school right now.
我可以留下來觀看。
I can stay and watch.
你是逃學。 你犯了罪。
You are truant. You're committing a crime.
我不會錯過任何重要的東西。
I'm not gonna miss anything important.
- 你怎麼知道的？
- 我讀。
- How do you know?
- I read ahead.
朝聖者使​​它的新世界。
The Pilgrims make it to the New World.
然後獨立宣言。
Then the Declaration of Independence.
是啊，你跳過了幾個世紀。
Yeah, you skipped a couple centuries.
史蒂夫？ Chrisann的在那裏。
Steve? Chrisann's out there.
我們走吧。
Let's go.
我可以讓我的情況下留？
Can I make my case for staying?
都能跟得上。
Nope.
- 她是我的。
- 加油。 你爸爸不希望我們留。
- She was with me.
- Come on. Your dad doesn't want us to stay.
這不是真的。 這不是...
That's not true. That's not...
你必須要在學校裏就是一切。
You have to be in school is all.
我犯了罪，現在，
我不想惹上麻煩。
I'm committing a crime right now,
and I don't wanna get in trouble.
你不是麻煩了。 我是開玩笑的。
You're not in trouble. I was kidding.
好。
Okay.
嘿。 什麼是第二個版本？
Hey. What was the second version?
你說的第一個版本是
少女。 什麼是第二個版本？
You said the first version was
girlish. What was the second version?
我真的不能想到的詞。
I can't really think of the word.
好。 好了，日子過好學校。
Okay. Well, have a good day at school.
- 遺憾。
- 什麼？
- Regretful.
- What?
就像希望你可以去
背部和做的事情不同。
Like wishing you could go
back and do things different.
你太年輕了，追悔莫及。
You're too young to be regretful.
不是我。
Not me.
此人演唱的歌曲。
The person singing the song.
得到它了。 遺憾。 那
有意義的，因為...
Got it. Regretful. That
makes sense because...
我想和你一起生活。
I wanna live with you.
六分鐘。
Six minutes.
- 你想看到斯卡利？
- 沒有。
- You want to see Sculley?
- No.
你知道那些時候，我
告訴你，你需要的安全性？
You know all those times I
told you you needed security?
這裏的原因。
Here's why.
我不知道是怎麼回事我已經
變老，你有沒有。
I don't know how it is I've
gotten older and you haven't.
一些交易與魔鬼
我從來沒有提供。
Some deal with the devil
I was never offered.
所以，你知道我一直
思為過去四年？
So you know what I've been
thinking for the last four years?
事實證明，約翰，我從來沒有
已知的是自己所想。
As it turns out, John, I've never
known what you were thinking.
沒有新生嬰兒有控制權。
No newborn baby has control.
你知道我在說什麼？
Do you know what I'm talking about?
在84年之前，蘋果推出。 你說...
In '84, before the Mac launch. You said...
- 是啊。
- 你說，正在通過意味著你沒有控制權。
- Yeah.
- You said that being adopted meant you didn't have control.
我們開始在一分鐘內，所以...
We're starting in a minute, so...
為什麼人們覺得我開除你？
Why do people think I fired you?
它的罰款，約翰。 這一切都在我們身後。
It's fine, John. It's all behind us.
是嗎？ 嗯？
Is it? Hmm?
不要打懵。 你不能把它關閉。
Don't play stupid. You can't pull it off.
你來這裏問我為什麼
讓人覺得你開除我嗎？
You came here to ask me why
people think you fired me?
為什麼人們覺得我開除你？
Why do people think I fired you?
只是確認我的東西，好嗎？
Just confirm something for me, okay?
你喜歡這個廣告，對吧？
You liked the ad, right?
商業...「1984年」 你喜歡它。
The commercial... "1984." You liked it.
- 你什麼時候拿到的傢俱？
- 這不是一個簡單的過程。
- When are you gonna get furniture?
- It's not an easy process.
它是。 你買一個沙發上，把它從那裏。
It is. You buy a couch, take it from there.
我想，如果你來真的很奇怪
這裏談談室內裝潢。
I'd be really surprised if you came
here to talk about interior decorating.
我喜歡的廣告非常多。
I liked the ad very much.
- 你做？
- 你知道我做到了。
- You did?
- You know I did.
你是一個說謊的兒子
婊子。 你試圖殺死它。
You're a lying son of a
bitch. You tried to kill it.
- 現在是時候認真考慮在Mac上。
- 這是過去的時間。
- It's time to take a hard look at the Mac.
- It's past time.
它的價格過高。 我們
需要將其拖放〜1995。
It's overpriced. We
need to drop it to 1,995.
我們需要雙倍的營銷預算，
We need to double the marketing budget,
把更多的機構內部硬盤驅動器
put more bodies on an internal hard drive
並投資於文件服務器。
and invest in FileServer.
- 到底在哪弄來我想殺的想法...
- 李克勞。
- Where the hell did you get the idea I tried to kill...
- Lee Clow.
- 他在說謊？
- 他是...錯了。
- Lee's wrong.
- He's lying?
- 會在哪裏的錢從何而來？
這將來自最後
- He's... mistaken.
- Where would the money come from?
擺脫蘋果II的。
蘋果II是
It would come from finally
getting rid of the Apple II.
唯一賺錢。
- 您同意審計委員會。
The Apple II is the
only thing making money.
- 我明白了董事會的關注，但我...
董事會的關注，
- You agreed with the board.
- I understood the board's concerns, but I...
我們沒有表現出產品？
- 別的不說，但我的問題是......
The board's concerns that
we didn't show the product?
- 什麼其他的事情？
我這麼問是因為我很好奇。
- Among other things, but my question was...
- What other things?
你說：「等等。」
除其他事項外，它是
I'm asking because I'm curious.
You said "among other things."
在一個反烏托邦星系設置。
它發生在一個星球
Among other things, it was
set in a dystopian galaxy.
我們不住。
天很黑，我們的品牌是相反的。
It took place on a planet
where we don't live.
和的我們沒有顯示產品。
It was dark and the opposite of our brand.
讓人津津樂道的廣告，但大部分
And we didn't show the product.
他們不知道我們在賣。
Mac電腦需要賣1995。
People talked about the ad but most of
them didn't know what we were selling.
有沒有市場調研告訴我們
The Mac needs to sell for 1,995.
在Mac失敗，因為它的價格過高。
它告訴我們，人們不喜歡它
There is no market research telling us
the Mac is failing because it's overpriced.
因為他們認為它不會做任何事情。
它的關閉，
It's telling us that people don't like it
because they think it doesn't do anything.
端至端。
我們不知道這是不是
It's closed,
end-to-end.
人們希望，但事實並非如此。
他們希望插槽，他們希望
We didn't know it wasn't what
people wanted, but it isn't.
選擇，他們想要的選項。
在路上，我們買的音響...
They want slots, they want
choices, they want options.
混搭組件。
約翰，聽我說。 誰
The way we buy stereos...
mix and match components.
說顧客永遠是對的
是的，我答應你，一個客戶。
John, listen to me. Whoever
said the customer is always right
- 它有它的光頭黨。
was, I promise you, a customer.
- 她被解放出來。
- 解放的光頭黨。
- It had skinheads in it.
- She was liberating them.
- 廣告沒有任何與他媽的光頭黨。
我們把他們當作他媽的演員。
- Liberating the skinheads.
- The ad didn't have anything to do with fucking skinheads.
甚至沒有人知道他們是光頭。
We used them as fucking extras.
我只是說，審計委員會關注...
Nobody even knows they were skinheads.
你發明了生活方式的廣告。
I'm just saying the board had concerns...
而我們的品牌是我的品牌。
You invented lifestyle advertising.
我的工作是使
And our brand was my brand.
推薦給董事會。
我們發現了很多的快樂
My job is to make a
recommendation to the board.
人們喝百事可樂。
我們沒有說世界就要
We showed a lot of happy
people drinking Pepsi.
最終，如果你買了胡椒博士。
建議我們放棄價格
We didn't say the world was going
to end if you bought a Dr. Pepper.
和雙倍的營銷預算。
- 我不能。
Recommend that we drop the price
and double the marketing budget.
-  和我們展示的產品。
我們發現它被打開，我們發現
- I can't.
- And we showed the product.
它傾倒，被消耗。
你要去做什麼，
We showed it being opened, we showed
it being poured, being consumed.
建議我們殺的Mac嗎？
我已經有了，史蒂夫。
What are you gonna do,
recommend that we kill the Mac?
什麼？ 什麼時候？
I already have, Steve.
你認為這個秘密對您的成功
What? When?
沒有假設人都知道
You think the secret to your success
做什麼用一罐汽水？
我沒有殺廣告，史蒂夫！ 我是
was not assuming people knew
what to do with a can of soda?
唯一的原因，它使人們對空氣。
剛剛。 一小時前。
I didn't kill the ad, Steve! I'm the
only reason it made it on the air.
我是從馬庫拉的房子來了。
Just now. An hour ago.
他說什麼？
I'm coming from Markkula's house.
- 他說什麼？
What did he say?
- 發明新的東西。
我給你一個團隊。 您可以在毛伊島坐。
- What did he say?
- Invent something new.
該度假村設有沙發。
I'll give you a team. You can sit in Maui.
等一下。 你是說你
The resorts come with couches.
建議終止在Mac
或者您建議採取
Wait a minute. Are you saying you
recommended terminating the Mac
我從Mac的球隊嗎？
我們買了三個景點中
or you recommended taking
me off the Mac team?
超級碗。 二30年代和60。
經過我們篩選吧，
We bought three spots in the
Super Bowl. Two 30's and a 60.
董事會希望這筆錢回來
他們問我賣掉了點。
After we screened it, the
board wanted that money back
Chiat / Day公司賣斷了
and they asked me to sell off the spots.
二三十的，但不是60，
我讓人們知道到李克勞
Chiat/Day sold off the
two 30's but not the 60,
如果他沒有嘗試很
and I let it be known to Lee Clow
不好賣的最後一個景點，
我也不會不高興。
that if he didn't try very
hard to sell the last spot,
如果我們放棄價格
I wouldn't be unhappy.
和雙預算...
價格下跌或兩倍的預算。
If we drop the price
and double the budget...
做到這一點的唯一方法是
Drop the price or double the budget.
拿錢出來的蘋果II的。
蘋果II應該為難
The only way to do that is to
take money out of the Apple II.
您。 這尷尬了我。
它不為難股東。
The Apple II should embarrass
you. It embarrasses me.
我不給一個關於股東狗屎。
It doesn't embarrass the shareholders.
這就是為什麼我雇你，所以我不知道
I don't give a shit about the shareholders.
有聽到股東。
股東是我的問題，
That's why I hired you, so I don't
have to hear about shareholders.
董事會代表股東。
這就是它是如何工作的。
The shareholders are my problem, and
the board represents the shareholders.
你確定這不是李克勞誰
That's how it works.
拖著腳賣60？
在我的方向，史蒂夫。
You sure it wasn't Lee Clow who
dragged his feet selling the 60?
你認為他會那樣做
At my direction, Steve.
對自己，把它做為自己？
是啊。 我想他會已經做了
You think he would have done that
on his own, taken it on himself?
什麼了，從你保存它。
- 我是唯一保護它。
Yeah. I think he would've done
what it took to save it from you.
- 你不想要的廣告
因為你試圖殺死
- I was the only thing protecting it.
- You didn't want the ad
蘋果前兩個月就推出。
你他媽的妄想。
because you were trying to kill the
Mac two months before it launched.
- 我可以提東西給你？
You are fucking delusional.
- 當然。
我沒有世俗的想法，為什麼你在這裏。
- Can I mention something to you?
- Sure.
為什麼以及如何離開蘋果公司的故事，
I have no earthly idea why you're here.
這是迅速成為
The story of why and how you left Apple,
神話，是不正確的。
- 我要借此向董事會自己。
which is quickly becoming
mythologized, isn't true.
- 不要那樣做。
- 我（上午）這樣做。
- I'm gonna take this to the board myself.
- Don't do that.
- 你不能。
為什麼？
- I am doing that.
- You can't.
他們認為你不再
Why?
要這家公司。
我得到的仇恨郵件，死亡威脅。
They believe you're no longer
necessary to this company.
我得到的死亡威脅。
I get hate mail, death threats.
我的孩子越來越嘲弄。
I get death threats.
為什麼人們覺得我開除你？
喬安娜的要叫我的名字在第二。
My kids are getting taunted.
Why do people think I fired you?
- 史蒂夫？
Joanna's gonna call my name in a second.
- 這是未經排練。
是的，我會在那裏，在短短一秒鐘。
- Steve?
- That was unrehearsed.
我在法庭上給你新的一天。
Yeah, I'll be there in just a second.
- 你給我？
I gave you your day in court.
- 我給董事會一個明確的選擇。
我說，「你想投資於蘋果
- You gave me?
- I gave the board a clear choice.
II或Mac嗎？「他們選擇了蘋果II。
誰曾想相同的人
I said, "Do you want to invest in the Apple
II or the Mac?" They chose the Apple II.
轉儲超級碗現場。
然後我坐上飛機到中國。
The same people who wanted
to dump the Super Bowl spot.
斯卡利先生。 有一個
And then I got on a plane to China.
要求你的一號線。
或者，我差點坐上飛機，
Mr. Sculley. There's a
call for you on Line One.
因為我在休息室的電話。
- 誰創造了這一呼籲？
Or I almost got on a plane,
because I got a call in the lounge.
- 無所謂。
這與我有關的。 誰打了電話？
- Who made that call?
- Doesn't matter.
約翰斯卡利。
It matters to me. Who made the call?
約翰？ 如果你上飛機，
John Sculley.
你已經失去了你
John? If you get on that plane,
工作由它的土地，時間
史蒂夫是被調用
you'll have lost your
job by the time it lands.
板。 他想你了。
我的行李上飛機。 我的
Steve's been calling the
board. He wants you out.
媽的還在北京的某個地方。
我拍了車回庫比提諾
I left my bags on the plane. My
shit's still somewhere in Beijing.
該他媽的半夜。
我知道這是什麼時候。 我需要的法定人數
I took a car back to Cupertino in
the middle of the fucking night.
這裏在一個小時內，我想史蒂夫在這裏了。
你把我關在Mac，
I know what time it is. I need a quorum
here in one hour and I want Steve here too.
它是壞的生意。
- 仲裁電話是一宗兇殺案。
You took me off the Mac,
and it was bad business.
- 在那裏！ 在那裏。
這就是一部分是廢話，我的朋友。
- The quorum call was a homicide.
- Right there! Right there.
這是一起自殺事件。
That's the part that's bullshit, my friend.
因為你知道你的
It was a suicide.
卡和我向您展示我的。
我給你我的，反正你做到了。
Because you knew your
cards and I showed you mine.
你以為我是什麼怎麼辦？
I showed you mine, and you did it anyway.
我好失敗，但我不會沒收。
What did you think I was gonna do?
我不是沒事失敗。
I'm okay losing, but I'm not gonna forfeit.
我們正在失去市場份額，
I'm not okay losing.
和Mac是賠錢的。
我們唯一的希望就是蘋果II，這是停滯不前
We're losing market share,
and the Mac is losing money.
因為它即將成為過時的DOS。
用戶已經在操縱他們的機器
Our only hope is the Apple II, which is stagnating
because of its soon-to-be-obsolete DOS.
到具有CP / M操作系統上運行
一個已經建成的英特爾運行。
Users are already rigging their machines
to run with a CP/M operating system
我不能把它更簡單莫過於此。
that's been built to run on Intel.
我們需要把我們的資源
I can't put it more simply than this.
到更新的Apple II。
通過從Mac獲取資源。
We need to put our resources
into updating the Apple II.
它的失敗。 這是一個事實。
By taking resources from the Mac.
- 它的價格過高。
It's failing. That's a fact.
- 有沒有證據表明它是......
我的證據！
- It's overpriced.
- There's no evidence that it's...
我是世界領先的專家
I'm the evidence!
在Mac，約翰。 什麼是你的簡歷嗎？
你發出矛盾的指示，
I'm the world's leading expert on
the Mac, John. What's your resume?
你是違抗命令，
You're issuing contradictory instructions,
你讓人苦不堪言。
我們的頂尖工程師
you're insubordinate,
you make people miserable.
逃亡到Sun，戴爾，惠普。
美股不知道
Our top engineers are
fleeing to Sun, Dell, HP.
誰在駕駛公車。
我們的價值損失了數億。
Wall Street doesn't know
who's driving the bus.
而我蘋果的CEO，
We've lost hundreds of millions in value.
史蒂夫。 這是我的簡歷。
但在此之前，你賣
And I'm the CEO of Apple,
Steve. That's my resume.
碳酸糖水，對不對？
我坐在一個他媽的車庫
But before that, you sold
carbonated sugar water, right?
沃茲尼亞克發明了未來。
因為藝術家鉛，
I sat in a fucking garage with
Wozniak and invented the future.
黑客要求舉手。
好吧。
Because artists lead and
hacks ask for a show of hands.
好了，這傢伙的失控。
All right.
我完全願意出手
Well, this guy's out of control.
在我的辭職今晚，
但如果你要我
I'm perfectly willing to hand
in my resignation tonight,
留下來，你不能有史蒂夫。
but if you want me to
stay, you can't have Steve.
安頓他。
Settle him out.
他可以保持股票的份額
所以他得到我們的通訊。
He can keep a share of stock
so he gets our newsletter.
，他將不得不切斷他
連接至蘋果。
He'll have to sever his
connection to Apple.
我死了嚴重的。 我想要的
呼籲投票的秘書。
I'm dead serious. I want the
secretary to call for a vote.
我他媽的敢。
I fucking dare you.
你已經做了一個出色的工作
這些年來培育的新聞。
You have done an outstanding job over
the years of cultivating the press.
而由，我的意思是操縱他們。
And by that, I mean manipulating them.
因為其中沒有，沒有其
編輯，沒有自己編輯的出版商
Because none of them, none of their
editors, none of their editors' publishers
這一天知道你強迫它，
to this day know that you forced it,
你迫使板。
that you forced the board.
即使我告訴你
正是他們想要做的，
Even after I told you
exactly what they'd do,
而這正是他們做到了。
which is exactly what they did.
一致通過。
Unanimously.
我沒有任何麻煩
記住的是，約翰，
I don't have any trouble
remembering that, John,
因為它是在
我生命中最糟糕的夜晚。
because of it being the
worst night of my life.
我不得不票，因為
我相信我是對的。
And I forced the vote because
I believed I was right.
我仍然相信我是對的。 而我是對的。
I still believe I'm right. And I'm right.
現在，我流血的夜晚。
Now I bled that night.
和我不流血。
And I don't bleed.
但是時間的完成了的事情，
But time's done its thing,
和我真的沒有
在一段時間想過這個問題。
and I really haven't
thought about it in a while.
現在，我絕對
理解你為什麼不高興。
Now, I absolutely
understand why you're upset.
和我想的人
知道事情的真相了。
And I want people to
know the truth too.
它的時間。
It's time.
得到它了。
Got it.
你會結束我的，是嗎？
You're gonna end me, aren't you?
你是荒謬的。
You're being ridiculous.
我會坐在中心球場
看著你自己做。
I'm gonna sit center court
and watch you do it yourself.
然後，我會為了一個漂亮的餐
一個1955年瑪歌，並簽署一些簽名。
Then I'm gonna order a nice meal with
a '55 Margaux and sign some autographs.
- 耶穌基督。
- 你想咨詢，百事一代？
- Jesus Christ.
- You want some advice, Pepsi Generation?
不要發送沃茲了一巴掌
我周圍的記者。
Don't send Woz out to slap
me around in the press.
任何人......你，馬庫拉，亞瑟岩石。
Anybody else... you, Markkula, Arthur Rock.
任何人，但雨人。
Anyone but Rain Man.
不要操縱他那樣。
Don't manipulate him like that.
無論你可能會想，我
總是要去保護他。
Whatever you may think, I'm
always gonna protect him.
來吧，史蒂夫。
Come on, Steve.
這就是男人。
That's what men do.
我們不能起步較晚。
We can't start late.
我不認為有什麼辦法
檢測在我的肩膀上的芯片。
I don't think there was any way
to detect a chip on my shoulder.
你知道嗎，回到Bandley，
Did you know, back at Bandley,
在Mac團隊每年都發表了獲獎
到誰能夠站起來，你的人？
the Mac team gave an award every year
to the person who could stand up to you?
沒有。
No.
- 我贏了。 三年成一排。
- 涼。
- I won. Three years in a row.
- Cool.
本。
This.
這......這傢伙川崎
在 Macworld大會。
This... This Guy Kawasaki
in Macworld.
他意外地得到了它的權利，不是嗎？
He accidentally got it right, didn't he?
你已經拖
你的腳在下一代操作系統
You've been dragging
your feet on the NeXT OS
直到你可以計算出
什麼蘋果會需要。
till you can figure out
what Apple's gonna need.
即使這是真的，這不
聲音的惡魔給我。
Even if that were true, it doesn't
sound that diabolical to me.
嘿。 我們已經準備好為您服務。
Hey. We're ready for you.
我是你最親密的紅顏知己，
你......你最好的朋友。
I'm your closest confidante,
your... your best friend.
你的事......你叫什麼呢？
Your thing... What do you call it?
你工作的妻子。 整個時間。
Your work wife. The whole time.
近三年。
The last three years.
你什麼時候改變主意，並開始
建設史蒂夫·喬布斯復仇機？
When did you change your mind and start
building the Steve Jobs Revenge Machine?
房子的一半。
House to half.
你還記得天空實驗室？
You remember Skylab?
這是一個無人的衛星國家航空航天局發射了
七十年代初期，在數據採集任務。
It was an unmanned satellite NASA sent up in
the early '70s on a data gathering mission.
問題是，當他們把它起來，
The thing is, when they sent it up,
他們還不知道怎麼樣
他們會拿回來。
they didn't know yet how
they were gonna get it back.
但他們覺得他們是非常接近
But they felt like they were close enough
，在八年是要去
是在那裏，他們會看著辦吧。
that in the eight years it was gonna
be up there, they'd figure it out.
他們在路上了。
They're on their way now.
他們沒有這樣做。
They didn't.
所以經過八年來，轟然倒塌
So after eight years, it came crashing down
在千里大片
整個印度洋。
in a thousand-mile swath
across the Indian Ocean.
小到左邊，
稍微向右，的
A little to the left,
a little to the right,
有人本來可以傷害。
somebody could have gotten hurt.
我真的想建立
一個計算機學院。
I really wanted to build
a computer for colleges.
該技術只是沒趕上
最多，因為我需要它的速度。
The technology just didn't catch
up as fast as I needed it to.
你知道我們出的錢。
You know we're out of money.
女士們，先生們，程序
將啟動瞬間。
Ladies and gentlemen, the program
will be starting momentarily.
但隨後蘋果停止創新，
我看到一些更好的東西。
But then Apple stopped innovating,
and I saw something better.
喬安娜，我知道學校是不是要購買
一個$ 13,000個字典，良好的揚聲器。
Joanna, I know schools aren't gonna buy
a $13,000 dictionary with good speakers.
你知道，我知道。
You know I know that.
但蘋果會。
But Apple will.
「原因阿瓦德斯·特凡尼安是要去
建立他們正是他們所需要的操作系統。
'Cause Avie Tevanian is gonna
build them exactly the OS they need.
他們會要我買了。
They're gonna have to buy me too.
對於半十億美元的股票
及端至端器上的每一個產品。
For half a billion dollars in stock
and end-to-end control on every product.
女士們，先生們，請歡迎...
Ladies and gentlemen, please welcome...
一年多後，這是第一次
推出業內人士介紹，
More than a year after it was first
unveiled to industry insiders,
下一台計算機是
終於可以在商店。
the NeXT Computer is
finally available in stores.
和它似乎是兩個
在連續的史蒂夫·喬布斯罷工。
And it appears to be two
strikes in a row for Steve Jobs.
學生和教育工作者
Students and educators
發現很難
證明了該機的性價比很高。
are finding it difficult to
justify the machine's high cost.
這麼多的黑色立方體。
So much for the black cube.
下一步剛剛出售了其工廠佳能
奠定了一半的員工。
NeXT just sold its factory to Canon
and laid off half its employees.
在計算機的世界裏，
它的殺人或被殺。
In the world of computers,
it's kill or be killed.
蘋果電腦已經陷入了困境。
Apple Computer has fallen on hard times.
這是裁員約2500人。
It is laying off about 2,500 people.
蘋果正在繼續
失去市場份額，
Apple is continuing
to lose market share,
沒有新的創新
管道除了牛頓，
with no new innovations in the
pipeline except the Newton,
CEO約翰斯卡利鍾愛的項目。
a pet project of CEO John Sculley.
如果你真的想成為
手機，你想要一個牛頓PDA。
If you really want to be
mobile, you want a Newton PDA.
但話又說回來，也許你不知道。
But then again, maybe you don't.
原來手寫
為電腦文本。
It turns handwriting
into computer text.
嘿，多爾夫，採取了備忘錄上
牛頓。 「打了馬丁。」
Hey, Dolph, take a memo on
your Newton. "Beat up Martin."
呸!
Bah!
1980年，蘋果不得不
市場的30％。的
In 1980, Apple had
30% of the market.
今天，蘋果只有3.2％。
Today, Apple has only 3.2 percent.
就是這樣。 約翰斯卡利
已經被Apple開除的。
That's it. John Sculley
has been fired from Apple.
那麼這個互聯網的東西呢？
你知道呢？
What about this Internet thing?
Do you know anything about that?
這是大的新事物。
It is the big new thing.
謠言到處亂飛
蘋果電腦再次
Rumors are flying around
Apple Computer once again
過誰將會接替掌舵。
over who will take over the helm.
在這一消息在這個時候，一個
卓越的高科技團聚。
In the news at this hour, a
remarkable high-tech reunion.
那麼，它的發生。 在
一個數十億美元的改組，
Well, it's happening. In
a billion-dollar shakeup,
蘋果收購了NeXT電腦公司
操作系統，這可能意味著...
Apple is purchasing NeXT Computer's
operating system, which may mean...
- 是浪子回歸？
- 賭注就可以了
- Is the prodigal son returning?
- Bet on it.
你猜怎麼了。 Mac是回來了。
Guess what. Mac is back.
- 蘋果聯合創始人史蒂芬喬布斯...
- 史蒂夫·喬布斯...
- Apple cofounder Steven Jobs...
- Steve Jobs...
- 史蒂夫·喬布斯...
- 史蒂夫·喬布斯...  - 史蒂夫·喬布斯...
- Steve Jobs...
- Steve Jobs... - Steve Jobs...
史蒂夫喬布斯重返蘋果。
Steve Jobs is returning to Apple.
如果要傳送的數字
從數碼相機拍攝的照片，
If you want to beam your digital
photographs from your digital camera,
它內置到每一個產品。
it's built into every product.
我們要的
新一代的I / O。
We're going to the
new generation of I/O.
十二兆USB。 兩個端口。
Twelve megabyte USB. Two ports.
我們把舊的蘋果I / O後面。
We're leaving the old Apple I/O behind.
立體環繞聲
內置到每一個產品，
Stereo surround sound
built into every product,
一個偉大的鍵盤和
你見過最酷的鼠標。
a great keyboard and the
coolest mouse you've ever seen.
這一次，我們用實際的小鼠。
This time, we used actual mice.
我們打​​開房子
在10分鐘內。 史蒂芬？
We're opening the house
in 10 minutes. Steven?
你想停止胡鬧？
Do you want to stop horsing around?
祝福我的眼睛。 這是史蒂夫
沃茲尼亞克坐在那裏。
Bless my eyes. That's Steve
Wozniak sitting out there.
給自己一個享受，並要求沃茲
如果他碰巧有正確的時間。
Give yourselves a treat and ask Woz
if he happens to have the correct time.
我有正確的時間，
我們正在消耗殆盡的。
I have the correct time,
and we're running out of it.
- 「一個偉大的鍵盤」......
- 偉大的鍵盤，你見過最酷的鼠標。
- "A great keyboard"...
- A great keyboard and the coolest mouse you've ever seen.
這就是那些東西看起來像今天這樣。
This is what those things look like today.
現在，我想告訴你什麼
他們會看起來像明天。
Now, I'd like to show you what
they're gonna look like tomorrow.
這是iMac電腦。
This is the iMac.
這是很酷。
That was cool.
沒有為什麼我喜歡
比我平時做的？
Why did I like that
better than I usually do?
- 我不知道。
- 有些異樣。
- I don't know.
- Something was different.
嘿，愚蠢的。
Hey, stupid.
我覺得她和你說話的傢伙之一。
I think she's talking to one of you guys.
- 你有沒有注意到有區別嗎？
- 這就是我...
- Did you notice a difference?
- That's what I'm...
退出跡象了。
The exit signs were off.
- 完全停電。
- 你做到了。
- Full blackout.
- You did it.
我們連線全部出口燈，以我們的董事會。
We wired all the exit lights to our board.
他們走出去的提示七
秒鐘，然後回來再打開。 從理論上講。
They go out with the cue for seven
seconds then come back on again. In theory.
- 我們認為這是合法的嗎？
- 沒有，我們非常肯定它不是。
- We think that's legal?
- No, we're very certain it's not.
- 你想看到一些報價？
- 讓我們暫緩的。
- You want to see some quotes?
- Let's hold off on those.
不，他會喜歡他們。
No, he'll like 'em.
- 我會展示給我看你以後。
- 我會帶著他們去了。
- I'll show 'em to you later.
- I'll take 'em now.
- 對不起。
- 從那裏把它撿起來，請。
- I'm sorry.
- Pick it up from there, please.
我們只有幾個
分鐘，所以讓我們只是做了360。
We only have a couple of
minutes, so let's just do the 360.
我們會帶出一個無線
相機我們從松下偷走。
We're gonna bring out a wireless
camera we stole from Panasonic.
我會告訴你這是什麼樣子。
I'll show you what this looks like.
整個事情是半透明的。
你可以看進去。
The whole thing is translucent.
You can see into it.
是如何形成的一種妥協，沃茲？
How's that for a compromise, Woz?
- 你仍然無法進入，但你可以看到到它。
- 很公平。
- You still can't get into it, but you can see into it.
- Fair enough.
我們把立體聲揚聲器
前方，右紅外在這裏，
We put stereo speakers in
front, infrared right up here,
CD-ROM驅動器的中間。
CD-ROM drive in the middle.
- 尼斯。
- 雙立體聲耳機插孔。
- Nice.
- Dual stereo headphone jacks.
所有的接口都在裏面
人靚一點這裏的門。
All the connectors are inside
one beautiful little door here.
以太網。 USB。
Ethernet. USB.
儘管這是一個
精力旺盛的Macintosh，
Even though this is a
full-blooded Macintosh,
我們針對它的頭號應用
we're targeting it for the number one use
消費者告訴我們，他們
想要一台電腦，這是...
the consumers tell us they
want a computer for, which is...
讓我們拿著它，請。 拿住。
Let's hold it, please. Hold it.
答案是「互聯網」。
The answer was "the Internet."
- 喬安娜？
- 是啊。
- Joanna?
- Yeah.
站在我的面前。 我想看看這些
報價，但我不希望喬爾知道。
Stand in front of me. I want to look at these
quotes, but I don't want Joel to know.
他們都是偉大的。
They're all great.
「這不僅是最酷的
電腦在幾年推出「
"It is not only the coolest-looking
computer introduced in years"
但胸部重創聲明
but a chest-thumping statement
「硅谷的最初的夢想
公司不再夢遊「。
"that Silicon Valley's original dream
company is no longer somnambulant."
這是一個詞。 它的意思是「夢遊」。
It's a word. It means "sleepwalking."
史蒂夫？ 對不起。 我們要清楚
房子如果我們的時間會啟動。
Steve? I'm sorry. We have to clear
the house if we're gonna start on time.
- 我們要準時開始。
- 我們絕對準時出發。
- We're gonna start on time.
- We're absolutely starting on time.
這裏。 拿著它。
Here. Take this.
每個人，僅此而已。 他們得
拖階段，重置並打開房子。
Everybody, that's it. They've got to
mop the stage, reset and open the house.
我愛你們。
I love you guys.
安迪，快點回來一分鐘。
Andy, come on back a minute.
- 哪一個？
- 赫茨菲爾德。
- Which one?
- Hertzfeld.
福布斯的調用它的
「行業改變的成功。」
Forbes calls it an
"industry-altering success."
看這裏。
Look here.
為什麼沒有我們曾經睡在一起？
Why haven't we ever slept together?
我們不是在戀愛。 看。
We're not in love. Look.
- 斯卡利。
- 你看他說什麼。
- Sculley.
- Look what he said.
「他已經實現了相同的簡單策略
，使得蘋果如此成功15年前...
"He has implemented the same simple strategy
that made Apple so successful 15 years ago...
使拳頭產品，促進
他們用出色的營銷。「
make hit products and promote
them with terrific marketing."
- 這是很好的了。
- 它是。
- It was nice of him.
- It was.
我是認真的。
I meant it.
J.D.塞林格的目擊是
比約翰·斯卡利更常見。
Sightings of J.D. Salinger are
more common than John Sculley.
我不是諷刺。
這是很好的了。
I wasn't being sarcastic.
It was nice of him.
- 你和他說話？
- 沒有。
- Do you talk to him?
- No.
自88年你還沒有和他談過？
You haven't talked to him since '88?
我會告訴你，如果我做到了。
I'd have told you if I did.
無所謂。
Doesn't matter.
我不希望人們
以為他們可以穿越我
I don't want people
thinking they can cross me
然後，繁榮15年
後來，我冷靜吧。
and then, boom, 15 years
later, I'm cool with it.
我是開玩笑的。
I was kidding.
有什麼問題你今天早上？
What's wrong with you this morning?
讓我們下車舞台。
Let's get off the stage.
「唯一蘋果公司提供
現在是在色調的領導地位。「
"The only thing Apple's providing
now is leadership in colors."
不用擔心這個。
Don't worry about it.
- 什麼是比爾·蓋茨都對我？
- 我不知道。
- What does Bill Gates have against me?
- I don't know.
你既出你的
頭腦。 聽我說。
You're both out of your
minds. Listen to me.
他放棄更好的了
學校比我退了。
He dropped out of a better
school than I dropped out of.
但是，他是一個工具包。 我會告訴你為什麼。
But he's a tool bag. I'll tell you why.
讓一切都與麗莎的權利。
Make everything all right with Lisa.
你知道，喬安娜？ 邊界。
You know, Joanna? Boundaries.
你來我的公寓
在凌晨1:00和清理它。
You've come to my apartment
at 1:00 AM and cleaned it.
所以告訴我在哪裏的邊界。
So tell me where the boundary is.
那裏。 比方說，它的存在。
There. Let's say it's there.
如果我給你一些真正的預測，
If I give you some real projections,
你能保證不
從舞台上重複呢？
will you promise not to
repeat them from the stage?
你是什​​麼意思，「真正的預測」？
What do you mean, "real projections"?
- 你是否被什麼給我？
- 保守的預測。
- What have you been giving me?
- Conservative projections.
市場一直在騙我？
Marketing's been lying to me?
我們一直在管理預期
所以，你不不。
We've been managing expectations
so that you don't not.
什麼是真正的預測？
What are the real projections?
我們要賣出一百萬
單元中的第一個90天。
We're gonna sell a million
units in the first 90 days.
20000一個月後。
20,000 a month after that.
- 神聖的狗屎。
- 是啊。
- Holy shit.
- Yeah.
你看？ 你等待足夠長的時間，並...
You see? You wait long enough and...
什麼是銷售收入，32％
What's more, 32% of the sales
打算去的人買
一個計算機首次。
are going to go to people buying
a computer for the first time.
和12％的將要使用的人
一些Windows機器中。
And 12% are going to people using
some kind of Windows machine.
這就是比爾·蓋茨對付你。
That's what Bill Gates has against you.
而這將是銷售最快的
計算機的歷史。
And it'll be the fastest-selling
computer in history.
你帶公司
從生活配套回來
You brought the company
back from life support
經歷苦難後，
中裁員3000人
after going through the misery
of laying off 3,000 people
和切割的產品線的70％。
and cutting 70% of the product line.
因此，史蒂芬，它結束了。
So, Steven, it's over.
你會取勝。
You're gonna win.
- 這將是犯罪不享受這一刻。
- 我很享受它。
- It would be criminal not to enjoy this moment.
- I'm enjoying it.
讓事情沒事了與麗莎。
Make things all right with Lisa.
- 你懂的...
- 加油。
- You know...
- Come on.
我不喜歡有少
隱私比其他人。
I don't like having less
privacy than other people have.
- 是否被一名億萬富翁採取​​一些刺斷了嗎？
- 沒有。
- Does being a multi-billionaire take some of the sting off that?
- No.
- 所有麗莎沒有...
- 所有麗莎所做的就是給她的祝福。
- All Lisa did...
- All Lisa did was give her blessing.
-  Chrisann賣掉了房子，...
- 和Lisa可以做什麼呢？
- Chrisann sold the house and...
- And Lisa could have done what?
她應該如何阻止她
母親賣自己的房子？
How was she supposed to stop her
mother from selling her own house?
我買了他們兩個。
That I bought for the two of them.
她應該如何阻止她？
How was she supposed to stop her?
清濁反對將有
一直在朝著正確的方向邁出的一步。
Voicing an objection would have
been a step in the right direction.
你不覺得你
有一個奇怪的過激反應
You don't think you're
having a bizarre overreaction
一個19歲的女孩讓
她的媽媽列出她自己的房子？
to a 19-year-old girl allowing
her mother to list her own house?
她可能已經嘗試過。
She could've tried.
當時她應該阻止她
媽媽，那個特定的母親......
Was she supposed to stop her
mother, that particular mother...
她給Chrisann福娃賣
房子，她這樣做是為了刁難我。
She gave Chrisann her blessing to sell
the house and she did it to spite me.
我不在乎，如果她把一個
管炸彈在熱水器。
I don't care if she put a
pipe bomb in the water heater.
你要修復它，現在。
You're going to fix it, now.
她一直怪怪的
個月。 她轉向了我。
She's been acting weird for
months. She's turned on me.
- 修好它。
- 什麼？
- Fix it.
- What the...
修復它，史蒂夫。
Fix it, Steve.
- 別緊張。
- 修復它，或者我不幹了。
- Take it easy.
- Fix it or I quit.
那個怎麼樣？ 我退出，
你不會再見到我了。
How about that? I quit,
and you never see me again.
那個怎麼樣？
How about that?
告訴我，今天早上有什麼地方弄錯了。
Tell me what's wrong with you this morning.
什麼是錯跟了我1​​9年。
What's been wrong with me for 19 years.
我是一個見證，我
告訴你，我已經串通一氣。
I've been a witness, and I
tell you, I've been complicit.
我愛你，史蒂夫。 你知道多少。
I love you, Steve. You know how much.
我愛你不在乎多少錢
人作出。 你在乎什麼他們做。
I love that you don't care how much money a
person makes. You care what they make.
但是，你做什麼是不應該
成為你最好的部分。
But what you make isn't supposed
to be the best part of you.
當你是一個父親，
When you're a father,
那是什麼的應該
是您最好的部分。
that's what's supposed to
be the best part of you.
而且這引起了我二十年
痛苦，史蒂夫，這是給你的
And it's caused me two decades of
agony, Steve, that it is for you
最不好。
the worst.
這是一個小東西。
這是一個非常小的事情。
It's a little thing.
It's a very small thing.
修好它。
Fix it.
現在修復它，或者你可以
與我聯繫，我的新工作...
Fix it now, or you can
contact me at my new job...
工作在任何地方我想要的。
working anywhere I want.
我不碰巧認為這是
一個小交易。 她知道...
I don't happen to think it is
a little deal. She knew that...
- 沒有。
- 我買的房子，兩個...
- No.
- I bought the house for the two of...
- 沒有。
- 你是什麼意思，「不」？
- No.
- What do you mean, "no"?
我的意思是沒有。 房子有什麼
做你為什麼生氣麗莎。
I mean no. The house has nothing
to do with why you're angry at Lisa.
我向你保證，房子什麼都有
做我為什麼生氣麗莎。
I assure you, the house has everything
to do with why I'm angry at Lisa.
你有沒有聽說過這句話
「現實扭曲場」？
Have you ever heard the phrase
"reality distortion field"?
- 是。
- 正如在「史蒂夫的現實扭曲場」？
- Yes.
- As in "Steve's reality distortion field"?
我聽說過它。 我讀過它。
它被傳唱給我的瓊貝茲。
I've heard it. I've read it.
It's been sung to me by Joan Baez.
你叫什麼現實扭曲場，
What you call a reality distortion field,
我敢肯定你
一個誰創造了一句，
and I'm pretty sure you're
the one who coined the phrase,
- 是我們在這裏的原因。
- 我知道。
- is the reason we're here.
- I know that.
如果我換我的銀行賬戶一塊錢
If I traded in my bank account for a dollar
每次有人告訴我一些
是不可能的，我會出人頭地。
every time somebody told me something
was impossible, I'd come out ahead.
- 我知道這一點。
- 什麼問題？
- I know that too.
- What's the problem?
- 我的問題？ 這肯定不是房子。
- 喬，我...
- My problem? It sure isn't the house.
- Jo, I...
這是你告訴她你
沒有打算支付哈佛。
It's that you told her you
weren't going to pay for Harvard.
那個孩子。
That child.
那認真的，unironic孩子。
That earnest, unironic kid.
她告訴你，我是不支付她的學費？
She told you I wasn't paying her tuition?
我應該打你
很久以前沉重的東西。
I should have hit you with
something heavy a long time ago.
麗莎告訴你我不支付她的學費？
Lisa told you I wasn't paying her tuition?
- 安迪告訴我。
- 哪一個？
- Andy told me that.
- Which one?
赫茨菲爾德。
Hertzfeld.
怎麼會赫茨菲爾德知道嗎？
How would Hertzfeld know?
他寫了哈佛做了檢查
25,000覆蓋學期。
He wrote Harvard a check for
25,000 to cover the semester.
你他媽的......他付了學費？
Are you fucking... He paid her tuition?
難道這不正是你剛才問見他嗎？
Isn't that why you just asked to see him?
不，我要求看他的東西...
No, I asked to see him about something...
你告訴她你是不是
要付學費？
Did you tell her you weren't
going to pay for college?
- 是的，因為...
- 你怎麼能這樣做呢？
- Yes, because...
- How could you do that?
因為她的母親，誰
也是她的房東...
Because her mother, who
is also her landlord...
赫茨菲爾德？ 我咆哮。
Hertzfeld? I was ranting.
我只是，你知道...我是
說。 你認為我會...
I was just, you know... I was
talking. You think I would...
我生氣了，因為麗莎
試圖讓我反感，喬安娜。
I was pissed off because Lisa
was trying to piss me off, Joanna.
這是她的意圖。 我不知道...
That was her intent. I don't know...
你明明嚇得屁滾尿流了。
You obviously scared the hell out of her.
赫茨菲爾德寫了一張支票
哈佛，支付...
Hertzfeld wrote a check
to Harvard, pay for...
- 她在這兒了嗎？
- 我敢肯定，她是。
- Is she here yet?
- I'm sure she is.
你能有一個人把她帶回來？
Can you have someone bring her back?
是。
Yes.
謝謝。
Thank you.
你懂的，
You know,
奶奶總是對我說...
my grandmother always used to say to me...
我不給狗屎，楊朵。
I don't give a shit, Yentl.
- 我會有人得到麗莎。
- 謝謝。
- I'll have someone get Lisa.
- Thank you.
如果你看到赫茨菲爾德...
And if you see Hertzfeld...
這是安迪。
It's Andy.
說曹操曹操的首席工程師。
Speak of the devil's chief engineer.
走。
Go.
進來。
Come on in.
你今天看上去很棒。
You look great today.
- 謝謝。
- 難道不是嗎？
- Thank you.
- Doesn't she?
她看起來棒極了。 總是這樣。 出去。
She looks fantastic. Always does. Get out.
- 嗯，我想我知道為什麼我在這裏。
- 你做？
- Well, I think I know why I'm here.
- Do you?
史蒂夫...
Steve...
- 你送支票了嗎？
- 是。
- Did you send the check yet?
- Yes.
因此，哈佛得到了學費支票
從安迪·赫茲菲爾德支付麗莎？
So Harvard got a tuition check
from Andy Hertzfeld to pay for Lisa?
我不認為他們的外觀，小心翼翼。
I don't think they look that carefully.
我不認為他們會通知
檢查不是來自你。
I don't think they'd notice
the check didn't come from you.
關閉之一。 這是
幾乎令人尷尬的我。
Close one. This was
almost embarrassing for me.
我瞭解...
I understand how...
我今天電匯你錢。
I'll wire you the money today.
我 - 我理解你的感受。
我道歉。 我願意。
I-I understand how you feel.
And I do apologize. I do.
但讓我告訴你我的想法。
But let me tell you my thinking.
我甚至不能想像一個適當的
比喻來形容你做了什麼。
I can't even think of an appropriate
analogy to describe what you did.
我知道你們會
修理東西。 你總是這樣。
I knew you guys would
fix things. You always do.
但在此期間，如果該錢不是
在那裏，她會想念學校的學期。
But in the meantime, if the money wasn't
there, she'd miss a semester of school.
- 是啊。
- 她不得不告訴她的朋友，為什麼。
- Yeah.
- And she'd have to tell her friends why.
而她需要的東西。 她需要的襪子。
And she needed things. She needed socks.
- 什麼？
- 這是冷在劍橋。 她需要溫暖的襪子。
- What?
- It's cold in Cambridge. She needed warm socks.
- 你給她的襪子？
- 好吧，我給她錢的襪子。
- You gave her socks?
- Well, I gave her money for socks.
你沒有得到臨時代理
自己作為她的中期。
You don't get to deputize
yourself as her interim.
你沒有得到重寫我的
決策。 你明白嗎？
You don't get to override my
decisions. Do you understand?
你沒有得到行動
就像你是她的父親。
You don't get to act
like you're her father.
必須有人來。
Somebody had to.
你剛才對我說什麼他媽的？
What the fuck did you just say to me?
我認識她，因為她6。
I've known her since she was six.
我也考慮...
I also consider...
Chrisann是我的朋友，外面什麼
你和我......我們的關係之外。
Chrisann's my friend, outside of what
you and I... outside of our relationship.
- 所以，你就像一個家庭顧問。
- 我是一個家庭的朋友。
- So you're like a family adviser.
- I'm a family friend.
那麼你可能知道，
Lisa的已經看到了治療。
Then you probably know that
Lisa's been seeing a therapist.
- 是啊。
- 很多年了。
- Yeah.
- For many years.
- 是啊。
- 如果沒有我的知識。
- Yeah.
- Without my knowledge.
這真的不是我的生意。
That really wasn't my business.
我被你迷住了
覺得是不是你的業務。
I'm fascinated by what you
think is and isn't your business.
麗莎已經持續到
治療師和她喜歡它
Lisa's been going to a
therapist and she likes it
並會為你的愛和
Chrisann她一起去。
and would love for you and
Chrisann to go with her.
你知道的原因是因為你
在一個推薦的治療師。
And the reason you know that is because you're
the one that recommended the therapist.
嗯，我知道一個人。
Well, I know a guy.
不，我的意思是你是一個誰
建議她去看心理醫生。
No, I mean you're the one who
recommended that she see a therapist.
你知道嗎？ 這是前一段時間，
我不記得怎麼整...
You know what? It was a while ago,
and I don't remember how the whole...
你告訴Chrisann說
麗莎應該去看心理醫生。
You told Chrisann that
Lisa should see a therapist.
史蒂夫，你誣蔑。
這是一個完美的標準...
Steve, you're stigmatizing.
It's a perfectly norm...
不是...
It's not...
我的一點是，它如何能傷害？
My thing was, how can it hurt?
讓我們來看看。
Let's find out.
Chrisann是我的朋友。
Chrisann is my friend.
- 什麼是你給的原因是什麼？
- 你意思是...
- What was the reason you gave?
- You mean...
什麼是你給Chrisann的原因
為什麼麗莎應該看到一個治療師？
What was the reason you gave Chrisann
why Lisa should see a therapist?
我不記得了。 我們
聊天，我說...
I don't remember. We
were talking and I said...
這幾乎是我剛才說的，
這當然不能傷害。
It's pretty much what I just said,
that it certainly couldn't hurt.
你不說，麗莎
需要一個強大的男性榜樣？
You didn't say that Lisa
needed a strong male role model?
我做到了。
I did.
我認為這是一個奇跡，她不劫財
銀行與共生解放軍。
I think it's a miracle she's not robbing
banks with the Symbionese Liberation Army.
我們沒有理由在
世界為什麼她應該是不錯的。
There's no reason in the
world why she should be nice.
但她。
But she is.
所以我幫，因為必須有人來。
So I helped, because somebody had to.
我將電匯錢給你，今天下午。
I'll wire the money to you this afternoon.
你在很久以前威脅我。
You threatened me a long time ago.
抱歉？
Sorry?
很久很久以前......你威脅我一次。
A long time ago... You threatened me once.
人們被吸引到人的天賦。
People are attracted to people with talent.
人們沒有它發現的威脅。
People without it find that threatening.
也許你應該去看心理醫生。
Maybe you should see a therapist.
當然不能傷害。
Certainly couldn't hurt.
我的意思是你從字面上威脅我。
I meant you literally threatened me.
在弗林特，前右在Mac推出。
At Flint, right before the Mac launch.
我重新編譯。 我以前是
嘗試調試的聲音演示。
I was recompiling. I was
trying to debug the voice demo.
你說，如果我不能找到一個解決方案，
你叫我在觀眾面前。
You said if I couldn't find a solution,
you'd call me out in front of the audience.
- 難道它說「你好」？
- 它做了。
- Did it say "hello"?
- It did.
沒有必要感謝我。
No need to thank me.
你為什麼希望人們喜歡你？
Why do you want people to dislike you?
我不希望人們不喜歡我。
I don't want people to dislike me.
我無所謂是否他們不喜歡我。
I'm indifferent to whether they dislike me.
既然沒關係，我一直有。
Since it doesn't matter, I always have.
真？
Really?
我一直很喜歡你
很多。 這太糟糕了。
I've always liked you
a lot. That's too bad.
- 敲'時間死了。
- 謝謝。
- Knock 'em dead.
- Thank you.
什麼是顯著的，什麼是
很難捉摸，但真正的，
What is remarkable, what's
hard to fathom but true,
是，對於給定的時鐘速率，PowerPC的
芯片快兩倍，奔騰II芯片。
is that for a given clock rate, a PowerPC
chip is twice as fast as a Pentium II chip.
換一種說法，
In other words,
一個266兆赫G3芯片
a 266 megahertz G3 chip
是快兩倍作為
266兆赫奔騰II。
is twice as fast as a
266 megahertz Pentium II.
或... 266 G3
Or... a 266 G3
等於大約500兆赫。
is equal to about 500 megahertz.
你知道什麼是
巧合的是，麗莎？
Do you know what a
coincidence is, Lisa?
看看字節
雜誌的字節標誌，
Take a look at Byte
magazine's Byte Marks,
金本位制任何...
the gold standard for any...
進來。
Come in.
我派人進大堂。
I sent someone into the lobby.
- 他們發現了她，她...
- 她在哪？
- They found her, and she...
- Where is she?
她說她寧願不回來。
She said she'd rather not come back.
- 為什麼？
- 這是它。
- Why?
- That was it.
- 我會在那裏我自己。
- 你不能。 你不能。
- I'm going out there myself.
- You can't. You can't.
這將是一個場景出來的
堅硬天的夜。
It'll be a scene out of
Hard Day's Night.
- 打擾一下。
- 嘿，喬爾。
- Excuse me.
- Hey, Joel.
安迪說，這是好回來。
Andy said it was okay to come back.
- 哪一個？
安迪 - 坎寧安。
- Which one?
- Andy Cunningham.
我不能這樣做下去。 我需要
其中一人改變他們的名字。
I can't do this forever. I need
one of them to change their name.
你叫安迪·坎寧安「安德烈。」
You call Andy Cunningham "Andrea."
不要緊，我給他們打電話。
It doesn't matter what I call them.
我知道是誰我說
對我說話的時候。
I know who I'm talking
about when I'm talking.
我需要其他人來
稱他們為不同的名稱。
I need everyone else to
call them different names.
給我一秒鐘。
Give me one second.
你可以去讓她給我，好嗎？
Can you go get her for me, please?
我剛才談到安迪。
I just talked to Andy.
赫茨菲爾德。
Hertzfeld.
我只是想洗刷本
我的大腦Drano的。
I'm just trying to scrub this
out of my brain with Drano.
但我想告訴麗莎。
But I do want to talk to Lisa.
好。 只是...
Okay. Just...
- 保持冷靜。
- 好。
- Stay cool.
- Okay.
謝謝。
Thank you.
嘿，史蒂夫。
Hey, Steve.
- 你感覺怎麼樣？
- 我感覺很好，喬爾。 你呢？
- How are you feeling?
- I'm feeling good, Joel. How about you?
我不認為我能在你的
商業。 它變化太快。
I don't think I could be in your
business. It changes too quickly.
好吧，我會死守，'你的事業即將
開始改變很快了。
Well, I'd hang on, 'cause yours is about
to start changing pretty quickly too.
這是在14第三次
多年來我寫你。
This is the third time in 14
years I'm writing about you.
你怎麼這麼遠覺得呢？
What do you think so far?
打擾一下。 Avie將的期待
為你。 他有一個新的鯊魚。
Excuse me. Avie's looking
for you. He has a new shark.
- 你要來後台一秒鐘？
- 當然。
- You wanna come backstage for a second?
- Sure.
- 這是誰呢？
- 阿蘭·圖靈。
- Who's this one?
- Alan Turing.
憑一己之力贏得了第二次世界大戰，
安可，發明了計算機。
Single-handedly won World War II and,
for an encore, invented the computer.
- 他會不會是運動的一部分，雖然。
- 為什麼不呢？
- He won't be part of the campaign though.
- Why not?
因為你剛剛問我他是誰。
'Cause you just had to ask me who he was.
我能看到新的鯊魚？
Can I see new shark?
我喜歡它比老的人好得多。
I like it better than the old shark.
- 鯊魚。
- Sharks.
- 有多少鯊魚你辦理什麼手續？
- 一對夫婦。
- How many sharks did you go through?
- A couple.
- 這是第39屆。
- 我們記錄在案。
- This is the 39th.
- We're on the record.
- 三十九鯊魚。
- 好。
- Thirty-nine sharks.
- Okay.
- 你知道什麼是特別的這條鯊魚？
- 什麼？
- You know what's special about this shark?
- What?
不，我要問的，因為它看起來
酷似等38個鯊魚給我。
No, I'm really asking, because it looks
exactly like the other 38 sharks to me.
讓我看看它與
果然不出所料，從輪廓。
Let me see it with the
cue, from the profile.
這是提示92-B。
This is cue 92-B.
這是一個配置文件在這裏，這
是什麼樣子的了。
This is a profile here, and this
is what it looks like from the back.
還有一件事。 它吃
奔騰筆記本電腦作為一種小吃。
And one more thing. It eats
Pentium notebooks as a light snack.
這是鯊魚。
This is the shark.
我很喜歡。
I really like it.
沒有人得到它在第一時間，
Nobody gets it right the first time,
但我已被證明
這條鯊魚15，20年前的魚。
but I should have been shown
this shark 15, 20 fish ago.
- 你可能是。
- 鎖入。
- You probably were.
- Lock it in.
10分鐘。
Ten minutes.
他通過採取咬自殺身亡
一個毒蘋果......阿蘭·圖靈。
He killed himself by taking a bite
of a poison apple... Alan Turing.
是啊。
Yeah.
應該有這個人的雕像。
There should be statues of that man.
他的名字應該在
學生的嘴唇。
His name should be on the
lips of schoolchildren.
七彩虹戰旗蘋果咬一口
取出來......那是哪裏來的？
The rainbow flag apple with a bite
taken out... That's where it came from?
不，我們把它撿起掉名單
友好的冠冕堂皇的話。
No, we picked it off a list
of friendly-sounding words.
但不會是巨大的，如果是
曾背後的故事嗎？
But wouldn't it be great if that
had been the story behind it?
史蒂夫。 挺喜歡過去的鯊魚。
Steve. Kinda liked the last shark.
你他媽的。
Fuck you.
我想請你幫個忙。
I wanted to ask you a favor.
我的朋友，很久以前，
My friend, a long time ago,
你之前問我一個忙
產品推出，我說沒有。
you asked me a favor before a
product launch, and I said no.
- 你想讓我承認...
- 不掛斷。
- You wanted me to acknowledge...
- Hang on.
如果你正要說你錯了，
我要準備這個記者。
If you're about to say you were wrong,
I want to prepare this journalist.
我是100％正確的，而你
是大錯特錯。
I was 100% right, and you
were spectacularly wrong.
但是，我還欠你一個人情，所以命名。
But I still owe you a favor, so name it.
史蒂夫...
Steve...
- 它不能承認的Apple II團隊。
- 確認蘋果II團隊。
- It can't be acknowledging the Apple II team.
- Acknowledge the Apple II team.
- 如何在私人？
- 沒有。
- How about in private?
- No.
- 這是一個惡作劇？
- 沒有。
- Is this a prank?
- No.
我試圖記住
一個300兆赫G3芯片...
I'm trying to remember that
a 300 megahertz G3 chip...
就在頂級球員。
Just the top guys.
史蒂夫。
Steve.
- 請原諒我，好嗎？
- 是的。
- Excuse me, okay?
- Yep.
一秒。
One second.
- 她說，她寧願不要。
- 什麼意思？
- She said she'd rather not.
- What do you mean?
她坐在她的朋友，
她說她寧願不回來。
She's sitting with her friends, and
she said she'd rather not come back.
好。 告訴她......把她放在一邊。
Okay. Tell her... Take her aside.
我不想為難
她在她的朋友面前。
I don't want to embarrass
her in front of her friends.
不過，告訴她，我只是害怕
狗屎了安迪，
But tell her I just scared
the shit out of Andy,
而這一次，沒有人是
她支付他媽的...
and this time, nobody's
paying her fucking...
好吧。 別這麼說。
All right. Don't say that.
但是，做你的事，其中
你的聲音聽起來古老而智慧
But do your thing where
you sound old and wise
由於廣泛的，悲慘
你生活的歐洲油畫。
because of the broad, tragic
European canvas of your life.
你知道我不是出生在一個
19世紀shtetl，對不對？
You know I wasn't born in a
19th-century shtetl, right?
請告訴她，這是非常重要的。
Please tell her it's important.
- 一切都好？
- 是啊。
- Everything all right?
- Yeah.
- 有些人在這裏，人...
- 我知道。
- There are people around here, man...
- I know.
- 包括新聞中的一員。
- 我看見了他。
- Including a member of the press.
- I see him.
沃茲。
Woz.
就在頂級球員，那些
誰是被解雇。
Just the top guys, the ones
who are getting laid off.
聽，好嗎？
Listen, okay?
去年，蘋果公司失去了十億美元。
Last year, Apple lost one billion dollars.
我甚至不知道這是可能的。
I don't even know how that's possible.
你均小於90
被破產天。
You were less than 90
days from being insolvent.
我有三個不同的會計師
試圖解釋給我聽。
I had three different accountants
try to explain it to me.
整個地方已被精簡。
The whole place has to be streamlined.
- 先從兩個會計師。
- 我開始與...
- Start with two of the accountants.
- I started with the...
- 喬爾，你能來台下？ 我們要去後台。
- 別管他那裏。
- Joel, could you come offstage? We're gonna go backstage.
- Leave him right there.
我開始通過Apple II團隊
因為我們不這樣了。
I started with the Apple II team
because we don't make that anymore.
- 只要承認的頂級球員。
- 有一個含羞草和放鬆。
- Just acknowledge the top guys.
- Have a mimosa and relax.
你不會放我鴿子，現在，史蒂夫。
You will not blow me off right now, Steve.
- 頂級球員應得的...
- 有沒有頂級球員。
- The top guys deserve...
- There are no top guys.
好吧？ 在Apple II
團隊，沒有頂級球員。
All right? On the Apple II
team, there are no top guys.
他們是「B」的玩家，而「B」
隊員勸阻了「A」的球員。
They're "B" players, and "B"
players discourage the "A" players.
我想「A」的玩家在蘋果公司，而不是戴爾。
I want "A" players at Apple and not Dell.
他們不是「B」的玩家，和
我是一個好法官說。
They're not "B" players, and
I'm a better judge of that.
從破產不到90天，
Less than 90 days from insolvency,
部分原因是有人認為
牛頓是不是一箱垃圾。
in part because somebody thought
the Newton wasn't a box of garbage.
- 喬爾，你能來台下，好嗎？
- 離開他。
- Joel, could you come offstage, please?
- Leave him.
我說的...
I'm talking about...
你們的設計和出貨
垃圾的小盒子，而我走了。
You guys designed and shipped a
little box of garbage while I was gone.
我說的是蘋果II，
I'm talking about the Apple II,
這不僅是一個關鍵
這家公司的歷史的一部分，
which is not just a crucial
part of this company's history,
它是一個關鍵的部分
個人電腦的歷史。
it is a crucial part of the
history of personal computing.
一時間。
For a time.
至少你可以做的，如果你
要縮小這些人...
The least you can do, if you're
going to downsize these people...
他們會住在最大的房子
對任何人的失業線。
They're gonna live in the biggest houses
of anyone on the unemployment line.
是承認他們。 確認
他們這期間推出蘋果II。
Is to acknowledge them. Acknowledge
them and the Apple II during this launch.
這是一個新的動物。
This is a new animal.
這整個地方是由蘋果內置
二。 您是由蘋果二世建造。
This whole place was built by the Apple
II. You were built by the Apple II.
作為事實上，我被摧毀
由蘋果II和其開放系統
As a matter of fact, I was destroyed
by the Apple II and its open system
使黑客和愛好者
so that hackers and hobbyists
能建造火腿收音機什麼的。
could build ham radios or something.
然後它幾乎摧毀蘋果
And then it nearly destroyed Apple
當你花了所有的錢，就可以了
when you spent all your money on it
並制定了宏偉的
總沒有新的產品。
and developed a grand
total of no new products.
- 牛頓。
- 垃圾的小盒子。
- The Newton.
- The little box of garbage.
你們想出了牛頓。
你希望人們知道嗎？
You guys came up with the Newton.
You want people to know that?
這是一個產品的推出，不是一個午餐會。
This is a product launch, not a luncheon.
我想過去的事情
做的是連接iMac電腦...
The last thing I want to
do is connect the iMac to...
為唯一中標產品
該公司已經做過。
To the only successful product
that this company has ever made.
我很抱歉，說白了，但
出現這種情況是事實。
I'm sorry to be blunt, but
that happens to be the truth.
麗莎是一個失敗。
在Macintosh上是失敗的。
The Lisa was a failure.
The Macintosh was a failure.
我不喜歡這樣說話，
I don't like talking like this,
但我厭倦了
林戈當我知道我是約翰。
but I am tired of being
Ringo when I know I was John.
每個人都喜歡林檎。
Everybody loves Ringo.
而我已經厭倦了被光顧你。
And I'm tired of being patronized by you.
你認為約翰成為約翰
贏得了抽獎活動，沃茲？
You think John became John
by winning a raffle, Woz?
你覺得他欺騙了別人
You think he tricked somebody
或打喬治·哈里森的頭？
or hit George Harrison over the head?
他是約翰，因為他是約翰。
He was John because he was John.
他是約翰，因為他寫道：「門票
乘坐。「我寫了蘋果II。
He was John 'cause he wrote "Ticket
to Ride." And I wrote the Apple II.
- 每個人？ 我想清楚了觀眾席。
- 沒有人移動。
- Everybody? I want to clear the auditorium.
- Nobody moves.
你做了一個漂亮的板，
You made a beautiful board,
其中，順便說一句，你是
願意給予了免費，
which, by the way, you were
willing to give out for free,
所以，不要告訴我你是怎麼建的蘋果。
so don't tell me how you built Apple.
如果不是因為我，你會是
最簡單的「A」在宅基高中。
If it weren't for me, you'd be the
easiest "A" at Homestead High School.
這些人生活和死亡您
讚美，所以這裏是你的機會。
These people live and die by your
praise, so here's your chance.
承認了好事發生
你是不是在房間裏。
Acknowledge that something good happened
that you weren't in the room for.
- 沒有。
- 史蒂夫。
- No.
- Steve.
做到這一點。 這是正確的。 其...
Do it. It's right. It's...
這是正確的。
It's right.
對不起，不行。
Sorry, but no.
然後讓我換一種方式。
Then let me put it another way.
我不認為有一個男人
誰在做更多的推動
I don't think there's a man
who's done more to advance
自帶民主化
與個人電腦比我有，
the democratization that comes
with personal computing than I have,
但你從來沒有給我任何的尊重。
but you've never had any respect for me.
現在，這是為什麼？
Now why is that?
我想至少要考慮的可能性
I'd at least consider the possibility
這是因為你
從來沒有什麼我。
that it's because you've
never had any for me.
這到底是怎麼回事？
What the hell is going on here?
什麼也沒有。 感謝您的時間。
Nothing. Thank you for your time.
搞定了。 她回來了。
It's done. She's coming back.
您可以從將來到一個半英吋
這家公司倒閉。
You came a half-inch from putting
this company out of business.
現在誰我看到了嗎？
Now who do I see about that?
我讓你保持你的工作。
I'm letting you keep your job.
你得到了一通。
You get a pass.
你知道，當人們常常問我
You know, when people used to ask me
什麼不同
我和史蒂夫·喬布斯之間，
what the difference was
between me and Steve Jobs,
我會說史蒂夫是大畫面的傢伙
I would say Steve was the big-picture guy
我喜歡上了一個堅實的工作台。
and I liked a solid workbench.
當人們問我什麼
所不同的是現在，
When people ask me what
the difference is now,
我說：「史蒂夫是一個混蛋。」
I say "Steve's an asshole."
你的產品有更好的
比你，兄弟。
Your products are better
than you are, brother.
這就是這個想法，兄弟。
That's the idea, brother.
而且知道，這就是區別。
And knowing that, that's the difference.
這不是二進制。
It's not binary.
你可以體面的，
優同時。
You can be decent and
gifted at the same time.
他不是故意的。
He didn't mean it.
是的，他做到了。
Yeah, he did.
他是一個喜怒無常的傢伙。
He's a temperamental guy.
不，他不是。
No, he's not.
這到五分鐘，每發射前，
It's like five minutes before every launch,
每個人都去酒吧，喝醉
並告訴我，他們的真實想法。
everyone goes to a bar, gets drunk
and tells me what they really think.
她來到你的更衣室。
She's coming to your dressing room.
我告訴你做的事
所有的權利與莉薩。
I told you to make things
all right with Lisa.
我並沒有說你必須解決
每血海深仇你。
I didn't say you had to settle
every blood feud you have.
上次血仇沒有解決，
我失去了封面時間。
Last time blood feuds weren't settled,
I lost the cover of Time.
雖然我用我的生命，我仍然不知道
什麼是地獄丹科特肯是生我的氣的。
Though for the life of me, I still don't know
what the hell Dan Kottke was mad at me about.
- 科特肯沒有失去你的封面時間
- 當然，他做​​到了。
- Kottke didn't lose you the cover of Time.
- Of course he did.
你願意讓我來證明
你的能力是錯誤​​的
Would you like me to demonstrate
your capacity to be wrong
當你確定你是對的？
when you're certain you're right?
丹科特肯告訴時間
雜誌，我被拒絕...
Dan Kottke told Time
magazine that I was denying...
你還記得的封面？
Do you remember the cover?
- 系統時間
- 是。
- Of Time?
- Yes.
- 是。
- 它以前如何？
- Yes.
- What was it?
- 你在說什麼？
- 什麼是在封面上？
- What are you talking about?
- What was on the cover?
- 一台電腦。
- 沒有。
- A computer.
- No.
這是一台電腦的雕塑。
It was a sculpture of a computer.
這是一個雕塑。
It was a sculpture.
時間將不得不有
提前委託它個月。
Time would have had to have
commissioned it months in advance.
你從來沒有在
對話為年度人物。
You were never in the
conversation for Man of the Year.
沒有人失去了你什麼。
Nobody lost you anything.
圖片我和Mac。的
Picture of me and the Mac.
那麼還有什麼是你確定？
So what else are you sure about?
我不知道我怎麼可能已經錯過了。
I don't know how I could've missed that.
- 現實扭曲。
- 不，嚴肅。
- Reality distortion.
- No, seriously.
認真。
Seriously.
不要試圖贏得麗莎的參數。
Don't try to win an argument with Lisa.
只要說你錯了。
Just say you were wrong.
來吧，親愛的。
Come on in, honey.
- 這不是「蜜」。
- 約翰。
- It's not "honey."
- John.
進去。進去，走出了大廳。
Get in. Get in. Get out of the hall.
我被帶到一個側門。
I was taken in a side entrance.
我會去出同
方法。 沒有人會看到我。
I'll go out the same
way. No one will see me.
- 你怎麼樣，喬安娜？
- 我很好，約翰。
- How are you, Joanna?
- I'm good, John.
我只是驚訝地看到你。
I'm just surprised to see you.
每個人都在這裏真的很感謝
報價你給福布斯。
Everyone here really appreciates
the quote you gave to Forbes.
- 你沒有做到這一點。
- 我的榮幸。
- You didn't have to do that.
- My pleasure.
如果你願意，我可以滑您在
回一次家的燈光熄滅。
If you want, I can slip you in the
back once the house lights go out.
- 我只是這裏說的「好運氣」。
-  好
- I'm just here to say "good luck."
- Okay.
你只需要一兩分鐘。
You just have a couple of minutes.
- 你會嘗試找到...
- 是啊。
- Would you try to find...
- Yeah.
你是個好人，約翰。
You're a good man, John.
所以，我給你的禮物。
So I brought you a present.
一個牛頓。
A Newton.
不要把它開箱即用，你就可以
把它賣掉，這是比我能說的。
Don't take it out of the box, you'll be able
to sell it, which is more than I can say.
一切都在那裏？
Everything all right there?
呃，不...
Uh, no...
只是一些喬安娜指給我看。
Just something Joanna pointed out to me.
我錯過了什麼那麼明顯有關...
I missed something so obvious about...
無所謂。
Doesn't matter.
你看，華爾街會坐下來
等著看你怎麼做的CEO，
Look, Wall Street's gonna sit back
and wait to see how you do as CEO,
所以不要讓任何波動
打擾你的頭12個月。
so don't let any fluctuation
bother you for the first 12 months.
當日交易者，因為我的回應。
Day traders are gonna respond.
我不需要上學你。
I don't need to school you.
這是你告訴我，我的方式
不應該殺了牛頓？
This your way of telling me I
shouldn't have killed the Newton?
最有效的動物
在這個星球上的禿鷹。
The most efficient animal
on the planet is the condor.
最沒有效率的動物
在這個星球上的人類。
The most inefficient animals
on the planet are humans.
好了，你不應該
殺害它雖然。
Well, you shouldn't
have killed it for spite.
這是不好的企業。 不要那樣做。
That's bad business. Don't do that.
但與自行車人
成為最有效的動物。
But a human with a bicycle
becomes the most efficient animal.
而正確的計算機...
And the right computer...
一個友好，易於計算機
這不是礙眼
a friendly, easy computer
that isn't an eyesore
而坐在你的辦公桌
張量燈的美女...
but rather sits on your desk with
the beauty of a Tensor lamp...
正確的計算機會
是一個自行車的想法。
The right computer will
be a bicycle for the mind.
你喜歡它嗎？
Do you like it?
我回饋。
I was giving back.
而如果代替它
在右手之中，
And what if instead of it
being in the right hands,
它是在每個人的手中？
it was in everyone's hands?
每個人在世界上。
Everyone in the world.
我們會談論最多的構造
在轉移，因為現狀...
We'd be talking about the most tectonic
shift in the status quo since...
曾經。
Ever.
我不知道為什麼你一直都是
感興趣的我收養的歷史，
I don't know why you've always been
interested in my adoption history,
但你說這是不是像有人
看著我，給我回。
but you said it's not like someone
looked at me and gave me back.
但是，這是發生了什麼事。
But that is what happened.
你告訴我你
有合適的電腦。
And you're telling me you
have the right computer.
這就是所謂的Macintosh。
It's called Macintosh.
律師夫婦收養了我第一次，
A lawyer couple adopted me first,
那麼一個月後給我回。
then gave me back after a month.
他們改變了主意。
They changed their mind.
然後，我的父母收養了我。
Then my parents adopted me.
我的親生母親
規定，凡帶我
My biological mother had
stipulated that whoever took me
必須是大專以上學歷，
富裕和天主教。
had to be college-educated,
wealthy and Catholic.
保羅和克拉拉喬布斯是
這些事，
Paul and Clara Jobs were
none of those things,
所以我的親生母親也不會
簽署的收養文件。
so my biological mother wouldn't
sign the adoption papers.
發生了什麼？
What happened?
有一個法律戰
這持續了一段時間。
There was a legal battle
that went on for a while.
我的母親說，她拒絕了
愛我的第一年。
My mother said she refused
to love me for the first year.
要知道，在情況下，他們只好給我回。
You know, in case they had to give me back.
你無法拒絕愛一個人，史蒂夫。
You can't refuse to love someone, Steve.
是啊，原來你可以。
Yeah, it turns out you can.
什麼是地獄可以了一個月之久的做
這是如此糟糕，他的父母給他回來嗎？
What the hell can a one-month-old do
that's so bad his parents give him back?
什麼也沒有。 什麼也沒有
一個個月大的可以做...
Nothing. There's nothing
a one-month-old can do...
你有沒有想過嘗試
找到你的親生父親？
Have you ever thought about trying
to find your biological father?
我見過我的親生父親。
I've met my biological father.
對於這個問題，所以有你。
For that matter, so have you.
這就是所謂的Macintosh。
It's called Macintosh.
- 史蒂夫·喬布斯先生。
- 詹達利。
- Mr. Steve Jobs.
- Jandali.
打個招呼約翰·斯卡利。
Say hello to John Sculley.
詹達利擁有的地方，
和約翰是百事可樂公司的首席執行官，
Jandali owns the place,
and John's the CEO of Pepsi,
，但我試圖讓他搬到
庫比蒂諾，把宇宙中的一個凹痕。
but I'm trying to get him to move to
Cupertino, put a dent in the universe.
你吃的素食主義者呢？
You eat vegan as well?
你在跟我開玩笑。
You're kidding me.
不，我會吃任何東西。
No, I'll eat anything.
你為什麼不與地中海開始
生菜沙拉，馬齒莧，薄荷...
Why don't you start off with the Mediterranean
lettuce salad with purslane, mint...
我的妹妹找到了他。
My sister found him.
- 他知道嗎？
- 不，事實上，他吹噓莫娜
- Does he know?
- No. In fact, he bragged to Mona
史蒂夫·喬布斯進來
餐廳所有的時間。
that Steve Jobs comes in
the restaurant all the time.
- 你不想...
- 沒有。
- You don't want to...
- No.
你不覺得你
應該跟他談談？
Don't you think you
should talk to him?
他很可能找個理由來告我。
He'd probably find a reason to sue me.
哦，史蒂夫...
Oh, Steve...
約翰，如果你在這裏對你的遺產，
John, if you're here about your legacy,
你需要形成背後沃茲尼亞克一條線。
you need to form a line behind Wozniak.
沃茲尼亞克的會沒事的。
Wozniak's gonna be fine.
我是誰開史蒂夫·喬布斯的人。
I'm the guy who fired Steve Jobs.
豐富，受過大學教育和天主教。
Rich, college-educated and Catholic.
史蒂夫？ 它的時間。
Steve? It's time.
我得走。
I've gotta go.
難道我這樣做呢？ 搞砸了？
Did I do this? Screw it up?
讓我們現在讓他走了。
Let's let it go now.
必須的時間。
Has to be time.
快來成為我們的CEO。
Come be our CEO.
是啊。 好。
Yeah. Okay.
這是手寫筆，約翰。
It was the stylus, John.
- 什麼？
- 我殺了，因為手寫筆的牛頓。
- What?
- I killed the Newton because of the stylus.
如果你拿著手寫筆，不能使用
其他五個連接到你的手腕了。
If you're holding a stylus, you can't use the
other five that are attached to your wrist.
我們可以一起做的事情。
Things we could have done together.
上帝，我們可能已經做過的事情。
God, the things we could've done.
我在為你付學費。
I'm paying your tuition.
你瘋了嗎？ 當然
我在為你付學費。
Are you crazy? Of course
I'm paying your tuition.
我一定是誤解你的時候
你說你不支付我的學費。
I must have misunderstood you when
you said you weren't paying my tuition.
你和你媽媽賣
房子是一個充滿敵意的事情。
You and your mom selling the
house was a hostile thing to do.
她需要錢。
She needed the money.
她總是需要錢。
She always needs the money.
她需要看醫生。 她
具有鼻竇感染。
She needs a doctor. She
has a sinus infection.
她有同樣的竇
感染自1988年以來。
She's had the same sinus
infection since 1988.
我要照顧我的母親。
我很抱歉，如果這激怒你。
I'm gonna take care of my mother.
I'm sorry if that angers you.
它激怒了我，因為你是一個孩子
It does anger me, because you're a kid
這不是你的工作，
照顧你的母親。
and it's not your job to
take care of your mother.
那是你是怎麼死的？
Is that how yours died?
夥計們，一步之遙，請，
給他們一些空間。
Guys, step away, please,
and give them some room.
當你的媽媽是90，不能養活自己，
When your mom is 90 and can't feed herself,
你可以照顧她。
you can take care of her.
但現在，她是45，完美
健康，不能養活自己。
But right now, she's 45, perfectly
healthy and can't feed herself.
你應該在努力工作，
學校是19，僅此而已。
You're supposed to work hard at
school and be 19, and that's it.
- 我相信你的母親。
- 保持這種好的表現。
- I'll take care of your mother.
- Keep up the good work.
- 什麼是地獄，你想從我這裏？
- 我被送到了。
- What the hell do you want from me?
- I was sent for.
我給她買了房子$ 40萬元。
I bought her a house for $400,000.
值得一兩倍多的今天。
It's worth twice that much today.
她賣了兩件法寶
岩石和一碗湯。
She sold it for two magic
rocks and a bowl of soup.
這是她的家。
It was her house.
她用這筆錢
通過歐洲旅行。
She used that money to
travel through Europe.
錢，你讓她討要。
Money which you make her beg for.
- 史蒂夫...
- 甚至不著手行動。
- Steve...
- Don't even start with that.
要安迪和要求的錢？
Going to Andy and asking for the money?
這是如此現成的圖表
過線？
That was so off-the-charts
over the line...
我沒有這樣做。 安迪來找我。
I did not do that. Andy came to me.
每個人都對這個評論？
Everybody have an opinion on this?
我很抱歉，夥計們。 在30秒內，
你要遲到了。
I'm sorry, guys. In 30 seconds,
you're going to be late.
她花的古董和再有錢
銷售他們的東西，她付出的一小部分，
She spends the money on antiques and then
sells them for a fraction of what she paid,
她做它用金錢
我給她給你。
and she does it with money
I gave to her for you.
史蒂夫...
Steve...
你來找我歇斯底里，當你13歲，
You came to me hysterical when you were 13,
- 問你是否能和我一起住？
- 我不是歇斯底里。
- asking if you could live with me...
- I was not hysterical.
因為你的媽媽
每天尖叫您。
Because your mom was
screaming at you every day.
十三是我第二次問你。
Thirteen was the second time I asked you.
她的生活壓力
作為一種精神治療師。
The stress of her life
as a spiritual healer.
我不相信，我說你是一個
壞人。 但是，如果我這樣做，我很抱歉。
I don't believe I said you're a
bad guy. But if I did, I'm sorry.
嘿。 事情發生在你身上，在學校，
Hey. Something happened to you at school,
一些第一學期的核心類
所有新生都必須參加...
some first semester core class that
all freshmen are required to take...
- 我讀時間
- 什麼？
- I read Time.
- What?
我在學校上網。
我讀的舊副本時，
I have Internet access at school.
I read an old copy of Time,
我問我媽一些
關於我家庭的歷史問題。
and I asked my mom some
questions about my family history.
這是...
That was...
時間寫了
錯位的一塊雜誌。
Time wrote a
mangled piece of journal.
你從來沒有要讀的。
You were never supposed to read that.
我有兩個不同的哈佛​​統計
I had two different Harvard statisticians
嘗試反向工程，
你想出方程
try to reverse-engineer the
equation that you came up with
證明美國的那28％
男人可能是我的父親。
to prove that 28% of American
men could be my father.
親愛的，我...
Honey, I...
你知道，我的母親可能是一個
陷入困境的女人，但什麼是你的借口？
You know, my mother might be a
troubled woman, but what's your excuse?
這就是為什麼我沒有留下深刻印象
與你的故事，爸爸。
That's why I'm not impressed
with your story, Dad.
這是你知道什麼
我所經歷的，
It's that you knew what
I was going through,
而你沒有做任何事情，
and you didn't do anything about it,
這使得你一個
不合理的懦夫。
and that makes you an
unconscionable coward.
而不是沒有，但
「想」是一個動詞，沒事，
And not for nothing, but
"think" is a verb, all right,
讓「不同」的副詞。
making "different" an adverb.
你問的人有不同的想法。
You're asking people to think differently.
你可以談談包豪斯運動
And you can talk about the Bauhaus movement
和布朗和「簡單
是精緻「
and Braun and "Simplicity
is sophistication"
與三宅一生制服
鮑勃·迪倫的歌詞你想要的，
and Issey Miyake uniforms and
Bob Dylan lyrics all you want,
但那個東西看起來像
朱迪傑特森的易烘烤爐。
but that thing looks like
Judy Jetson's Easy-Bake oven.
嘿。
Hey.
你要去起步較晚。
You're gonna start late.
- 你知道麗莎主張？
- 什麼？
- You know what Lisa stood for?
- What?
計算機。 該麗莎。
你知道這是什麼主張？
The computer. The Lisa.
You know what it stood for?
對不起，我說，對
iMac電腦。 這不是我的真實想法。
I'm sorry I said that about the
iMac. It's not what I really think.
在我背後，在辦公室，
你知道這是什麼主張？
Behind my back, at the office,
you know what it stood for?
本地集成系統
建築。 我五歲。
Local Integrated System
Architecture. I was five.
- 你為什麼不能只是躺在？
- 我做到了。
- Why couldn't you just lie?
- I did.
當然，這是後命名。
Of course it was named after you.
本地集成系統架構
甚至不意味著任何東西。
Local Integrated System Architecture
doesn't even mean anything.
為什麼你說這是不是所有的那些年？
Why'd you say it wasn't all those years?
我真的不知道。
I honestly don't know.
為什麼你說你不是我的父親？
Why'd you say you weren't my father?
我不好做。
I'm poorly made.
- 這是9點以後。 你要遲到了。
- 我不在乎。
- It's after 9:00. You're gonna be late.
- I don't care.
- 你寫的深紅
- 什麼？
- You're writing for the Crimson.
- What?
的蘋果章
哈佛校友會
The Apple chapter of the
Harvard Alumni Association
告訴我你寫
對於深紅。
tells me you're writing
for the Crimson.
哦。 是的，一點點。 雜文。
Oh. Yeah, a little bit. Essays.
- 我想讀之一。
- 當然。
- I'd like to read one.
- Sure.
不，我的意思了。 我想
讀你的文章之一了。
No, I mean now. I'd like to
read one of your essays now.
加油。 你必須去在舞台上。
Come on. You've got to go on stage.
在iMac將無法啟動，直到
你給我你的論文之一。
The iMac will not be launched until
you give me one of your essays,
所以世界正等著你。
so the world is waiting for you.
我真的很抱歉，夥計們。
I'm really sorry, guys.
祝你好運。
Good luck.
我要去把音樂在你的口袋裏。
I'm gonna put music in your pocket.
什麼？
What?
百首歌曲。 一千首歌曲。 500首歌曲。
Hundred songs. A thousand songs. 500 songs.
介於500和
幾千首歌曲就在你的口袋裏，
Somewhere between 500 and a
thousand songs right in your pocket,
因為我不能忍受看著
那令人費解的Walkman了。
'cause I can't stand looking at
that inexplicable Walkman anymore.
你帶著一個
磚播放盒式磁帶上。
You're carrying around a
brick playing cassette tape.
我們不是野蠻人。
We're not savages.
所以我要把一千
歌曲在你的口袋裏。
So I'm gonna put a thousand
songs in your pocket.
- 你能做到嗎？
- 嗯 - 嗯。
- You can do that?
- Mm-hmm.
♪我們會得到濕透
權利，通過♪
♪ We'd get soaked
right through ♪
♪我們曾經告訴他們
我住在你的♪
♪ We used to tell them
I was staying at yours ♪
♪躲藏在我們自己的世界♪
♪ Sheltered in our own world ♪
你想從後台看？
You want to watch from backstage?
好。
Okay.
♪我們從小就在午夜♪
♪ We grew up at midnight ♪
轉到線索之一。
Go cue one.
♪我們只是孩子，然後♪
♪ We were only kids then ♪
♪愛的女人，充滿愛心的人♪
♪ Loving woman, loving man ♪
♪在這裏為你，做
最好的，我們可以♪
♪ Here for you, doing
the best we can ♪
♪很難弄清楚，難以承擔♪
♪ Hard to figure, hard to bear ♪
♪很難想知道
你有多在乎♪
♪ Hard to think knowing
how much you care ♪
♪這是奇怪的事情
風雨同舟♪
♪ It's the strangest thing
through thick and thin ♪
♪這一切時間保持
承諾所做♪
♪ All this time kept
the promise you made ♪
♪如果你告訴，
我會告訴♪
♪ If you're telling,
I'll be told ♪
♪我會來的運行，並
還有，只要我能♪
♪ I'll come running and be
there as soon as I can ♪
♪窗外，
我被困在你♪
♪ Outside of the window,
I was stuck on you ♪
♪我們只是孩子，然後♪
♪ We were only kids then ♪
♪我住在你的♪
♪ I was staying at yours ♪
你還記得畫
你做了原始的Mac上？
You remember that painting
you did on the original Mac?
我願意。
I do.
女士們，先生們，
Ladies and gentlemen,
史蒂夫·喬布斯。
Steve Jobs.
♪我們從小就在午夜♪
♪ We grew up at midnight ♪
♪我們只是孩子，然後♪
♪ We were only kids then ♪
♪我們從小就在午夜♪
♪ We grew up at midnight ♪
♪我們只是孩子，然後♪
♪ We were only kids then ♪
沃茲。
Woz.
♪但是那天晚上我們知道♪
♪ But that night we knew ♪
喔！
Whoo!
同步和改正explosiveskull
www.addic7ed.com。
Sync and corrections by explosiveskull
www.addic7ed.com.
♪「特瓦在另一一生，
辛勞和血液中的一個♪
♪ 'Twas in another lifetime,
one of toil and blood ♪
♪當黑暗是一種美德，
路上滿是泥濘的♪
♪ When blackness was a virtue,
the road was full of mud ♪
♪我在他從荒野，
♪形式的生物無效
♪ I came in from the wilderness,
a creature void of form ♪
♪「進來吧，」她說，「我給
你從風暴「♪的庇護
♪ "Come in," she said, "I'll give
you shelter from the storm" ♪
♪如果我通過這種方式
再次，你可以放心♪
♪ And if I pass this way
again, you can rest assured ♪
♪我會永遠做
我對她最好的♪
♪ I'll always do
my best for her ♪
♪在那，我給我的話♪
♪ On that, I give my word ♪
♪在世界
鋼眼睛死亡♪
♪ In a world of
steel-eyed death ♪
♪和男人誰是
戰鬥熱情♪
♪ And men who are
fighting to be warm ♪
♪「進來吧，」她說，「我給
你從風暴「♪的庇護
♪ "Come in," she said, "I'll give
you shelter from the storm" ♪
♪沒有一個字是
我們之間說話♪
♪ Not a word was
spoke between us ♪
♪有一點
風險參與♪
♪ There was little
risk involved ♪
♪一切到這一點
一直沒有解決♪
♪ Everything up to that point
had been left unresolved ♪
♪試著想像一個地方，
它總是安全和溫暖♪
♪ Try imagining a place where
it's always safe and warm ♪
♪「進來吧，」她說，「我給
你從風暴「♪的庇護
♪ "Come in," she said, "I'll give
you shelter from the storm" ♪
♪我被燒壞
從疲憊♪
♪ I was burned out
from exhaustion ♪
♪埋在冰雹♪
♪ Buried in the hail ♪
♪中毒草叢
而吹出來的線索♪
♪ Poisoned in the bushes
and blown out on the trail ♪
♪獵殺像鱷魚，
肆虐在玉米♪
♪ Hunted like a crocodile,
ravaged in the corn ♪
♪「進來吧，」她說，「我給
你從風暴「♪的庇護
♪ "Come in," she said, "I'll give
you shelter from the storm" ♪
♪突然我轉身
她站在那裏♪
♪ Suddenly I turned around
and she was standing there ♪
♪隨著她的銀色手鐲
手腕和鮮花在她的頭髮♪
♪ With silver bracelets on her
wrists and flowers in her hair ♪
♪她走上前去
我這麼優雅♪
♪ She walked up to
me so gracefully ♪
♪握住我的荊棘冠♪
♪ And took my crown of thorns ♪
♪「進來吧，」她說，「我給
你從風暴「♪的庇護
♪ "Come in," she said, "I'll give
you shelter from the storm" ♪
♪現在有一個
我們之間的牆♪
♪ Now there's a
wall between us ♪
♪有些東西一直遺失♪
♪ Something there's been lost ♪
♪我花了太想當然，
我得到了我的信號越過♪
♪ I took too much for granted,
I got my signals crossed ♪
♪只是認為這一切
開始於一個平靜的早晨♪
♪ Just to think that it all
began on an uneventful morn ♪
♪「進來吧，」她說，「我給
你從風暴「♪的庇護
♪ "Come in," she said, "I'll give
you shelter from the storm" ♪
♪好，副
走在堅硬的指甲♪
♪ Well, the deputy
walks on hard nails ♪
♪以及傳教士
騎坐騎♪
♪ And the preacher
rides a mount ♪
♪但沒有真正
問題太多♪
♪ But nothing really
matters much ♪
♪這是單獨的厄運，計數♪
♪ It's doom alone that counts ♪
♪以及獨眼承辦，
他吹徒勞的號角♪
♪ And the one-eyed undertaker,
he blows a futile horn ♪
♪「進來吧，」她說，「我給
你從風暴「♪的庇護
♪ "Come in," she said, "I'll give
you shelter from the storm" ♪
♪我聽到新生嬰兒
嗷像哀鴿♪
♪ I've heard newborn babies
wailing like a mourning dove ♪
♪老男人與破
牙滯留不愛♪
♪ And old men with broken
teeth stranded without love ♪
♪我是否理解
你的問題，人呢？ ♪
♪ Do I understand
your question, man? ♪
♪它是絕望和凄涼？ ♪
♪ Is it hopeless and forlorn? ♪
♪「進來吧，」她說，「我給
你從風暴「♪的庇護
♪ "Come in," she said, "I'll give
you shelter from the storm" ♪
感謝explosiveskull的子
www.addic7ed.com。
Thanks to explosiveskull for the Sub
www.addic7ed.com.
希望它幫助 -  bozxphd  \NHope it helped - bozxphd